Mr. cox?
考克斯先生
Guys, l need cox.
夥計們  考克斯先生呢
He goes on in two minutes and l can't find him.
他兩分鐘後就要上台  我現在卻找不到他
Mr. cox.
考克斯先生
You're gonna have to give him a moment, son.
讓他自己呆一會吧  孩子
Dewey cox needs to think about his entire life
杜威·考克斯需要在表演之前
before he plays.
好好思考一下他整個一生
Come on, nate, let's go play.
內特  我們去玩吧
I can't, dewey. l gotta practice.
不行杜威  我要練習呢
You can't practice all the time, nate. you're already perfect.
你不能老是練習  內特  你已經彈得很好了
All right. come on, dewey, let's go play!
好吧  走  杜威  我們去玩吧
-today's gonna be the best day ever! -yeah!
-今天將會是有史以來最美好的一天  -對
Ain't nothing horrible gonna happen today.
今天不會發生什麼讓人討厭的事情的
What do you wanna be when you grow up, dewey?
杜威  你長大後想成為怎樣的人
I don't know. never really think about it before.
不知道  我還真的沒想過呢
When l grow up, l'm gonna be a great composer.
我長大後要成為一個偉大的作曲家
And a professional baseball player.
和一個職業棒球手
Then l'm gonna be an astronaut, and l'm gonna go to the moon.
我還要成為宇航員  登上月球
There's nothing l won't do with this long, long life of mine.
在這麼長的一生中  我什麼都想嘗試一下
For sure.
那當然
That's what's great about being young.
當個小孩子真好  還有那麼多時間來做大事情
so much time to do great things.
有那麼多時間可以來準備做大事情
Let's go play!
我們去玩吧
My turn!
輪到我了
I got him! I got him!
我抓到了  我抓到了
Catch!
接住
Chicken!
衝啊
I challenge you to a duel, sir.
我準備好來和你決鬥了  先生
I don't know, nate.
我不知道  內特
You know how mad pa gets when we play with his machetes.
如果我們用這把刀玩  爸爸會很生氣的
Come on. there's nothing wrong with a little machete-fighting.
別擔心  來一場小戰鬥沒什麼大不了的
Now, en garde!
開始了  你輸吧
-do you yield, sir? -never!
-你投降嗎  先生  -不
Prepare to meet your maker.
準備去見上帝吧
-dewey! -nate!
-杜威  -內特
I'm halved!
我成兩半了
Oh, we should've listened to pa.
我們應該聽爸爸的話的
Dewey, l'm cut in half pretty bad.
杜威  我被切成兩段了
In case l don't make it, then you'll have to be double great...
萬一我裝回不去了  那你就要擁有
...for the both of us.
我們兩個人的力量了
Wow, that's a lot of pressure, nate.
我不行的  內特
You can handle it, dewey. now, run, get pa!
你行的  杜威  現在快去找爸爸
Holy shit.
真見鬼
This was a particularly bad case of somebody being cut in half.
他被砍成了兩段  那可真是太糟糕了
I was not able to reattach the top half of his body...
我可沒法把他的上半身
...to the bottom half of his body.
重新連到他的下半身了
Speak english, doc! we ain't scientists.
別講的那麼專業  醫生  我們不是科學家
I'm sorry, folks. he's gone.
對不起  夥計  他死了
Oh, no!
噢  不
Oh, my god.
上帝啊
Dear god. oh, dewey.
上帝啊  杜威
It's all your fault, dewey cox.
都是你幹的  杜威·考克斯
Oh, pa, you don't mean that. lt's not his fault.
別這麼說  這不是他的錯
He cut him in half with a machete.
他用刀把他弟弟切成了兩半
No.
不
You. you're not half the boy that nate was.
你連內特的一半都比不上
You're not even half the boy that the top half of nate was...
在他被砍成了兩半之後
...after you cut him in half.
你甚至連他上半身的一半都比不上
So you're saying l'm less than a quarter of the boy nate was?
你是說我連內特的四分之一都沒有
The wrong kid died.
孩子死錯了
Ma, l can't smell anything.
媽咪  我的鼻子聞不到氣味了
You can't smell anything?
你聞不到氣味了嗎
I think l lost my sense of smell.
我想我失去了嗅覺
You gone smell-blind, son.
兒子  你得嗅覺癥了
It'll pass, dewey.
一切都會過去的  杜威
Now, you run on down to the country store
你現在去商店
and get us some butter.
買點黃油
And a candle.
和一根蠟燭回來
We're gonna light us a candle tonight.
今晚我們要為內特點一根蠟燭
I'm a gamblin' man
我是個冒險家
I gambled everywhere I go
我到處去冒險
Lord, I'm a gamblin' man
神啊  我是個冒險家
I'm a gamblin' man
我是個冒險家
Lord, I gambled from door to door
神啊  我的冒險旅程永不停步
I've never heard no music like that before.
我從來沒聽過這樣的音樂
It's so sad.
太悲傷了
That's why it's called the blues, boy.
這就叫作憂鬱的布魯斯  孩子
I think l'd like to play me some blues.
我想為自己演奏一下布魯斯
Ain't no 6-year-old boy
一個6歲的孩子
understand the true meaning of the blues.
是不會懂得布魯斯音樂的真諦的
I reckon l might.
我覺得我懂
You play the guitar?
你會彈吉它嗎
Never have before. but l'm a real fast learner.
從來沒碰過  不過我學得很快
Well, go ahead.
好  試試吧
You put your finger right up there.
把你的指頭放在那裡
place your hands here. that's it.
手放這裡  就這樣
That's the g chord.
這是G調和弦
Now hit the strings with your other hand.
現在用另一隻手撥弦
-that's it. -there you go.
-就這樣  -開始吧
That ain't bad.
還不錯
I done a bad thing
我做了件蠢事
Cut my brother in half
把我哥哥切成了兩半
I done a bad, bad thing
我做了件很蠢很蠢的事
My mama's gonna cry
我媽媽傷心得哭了
Somewhere the devil's havin' a laugh
魔鬼卻開心地笑著
It's not bad for your first time.
第一次彈還不錯
You can do it, dewey. you'll be double great.
你能做到的  杜威  你會做的更好的
For the both of us.
只要有我們兩個人的力量
Dewey?
杜威
Mama, you made it!
媽媽  你終於來了
There's my favorite 14-year-old son.
我14歲的兒子啊 我可喜歡你了
Oh, no. come on, now. not in front of the fellas.
噢  不要在那麼多人面前這樣
Howdy, boys.
你們好  孩子們
Howdy, mrs. cox.
你好  考克斯夫人
I just wanted to say break a leg.
我只想說  祝你們好運
I know you boys are gonna play a real good song.
我知道你們會演奏一首很好聽的歌
Oh, thanks, ma.
謝謝  媽媽
I'm just so proud you learned to play the guitar so good.
你吉它彈得這麼好  我真感到驕傲
Without even having a sense of smell.
儘管你失去了嗅覺
It's all right now, mama. l learned how to play by ear.
沒事了  媽媽  是我的耳朵教會了音樂
You just go out there and sing your heart out.
你只要站在那裡  用心去唱就行了
I will, mama.
我會的  媽媽
I don't know what we're doing here
我不知道我們來參加這
at this high school talent show.
中學才藝表演來幹什麼
We're here to see our boy, that's what we're doing here.
我們來看我們的孩子  這就是我們要做的
You all right, ma'am?
你沒事吧  夫人
I'm fine.
我很好
Just my vertigo acting up again.
剛才我的麻痹癥又犯了
-what's vertigo? -just a little dizziness is all.
-什麼是眩暈癥?  -就是有點頭昏眼花
Ain't nothing terrible ever came from no dizziness.
頭昏眼花不會引起什麼大病的
Testing, testing.
喂  喂
Hello, everybody. welcome to the annual talent show.
大家好  歡迎來到一年一度的才藝表演大會
We're gonna get this going here with the juggling talents of johnny mcgraw.
下面先讓約翰尼·麥格拉來為我們表演雜技
-how we gonna follow that? -delilah montgomery.
-這麼精彩  我們怎麼繼續  -黛利拉·蒙哥馬利
-delilah montgomery. -very nice!
-黛利拉·蒙哥馬利  -太棒了
And now sophomore dewey cox is gonna sing us a song.
現在我們的二年級學生杜威·考克斯給我們帶來一首歌
So, ladies and germs....
女士們  先生們
I know, l know.
我知道  我知道
Please welcome dewey cox and the dewey cox four.
以熱烈的掌聲來歡迎杜威·考克斯和他的四人組合
Hi. my name's dewey cox.
大家好  我叫杜威·考克斯
And this is a little song l wrote called 'take my hand.''
這首我的自創曲  名字叫'牽我的手'
I sure hope you like it.
希望大家能夠喜歡
The wrong kid died, goddamn it.
孩子死錯了  見鬼
-take -take, take
-來吧  -來吧  來吧
Take my hand
牽我的手吧
We're gonna walk through the park
我們正要穿過公園
I promise to have you home before dark
我答應你在天黑前帶你回家
Home before dark
天黑前回家
Oh, life would be so sweet
喔  生活是多麼美好
Walking with you down the street
與你一起走過的街道
This music is an outrage!
這首歌太露骨了!
Come on and take my hand
來吧  牽我的手吧
It's the devil's music!
這是魔鬼才唱的音樂
It's all right if you're coy
你的害羞讓我沉醉
After all I'm a boy
畢竟我還是個男孩
And you're a girl
而你是個女孩
But make no mistake
但這並沒有錯
Yours is the hand I want to take
而我只想牽你的手
So please
那麼  來吧
So please, please
那麼來吧  來吧
Take my hand
牽著我的手吧
You're going to hell!
下地獄去吧
Blasphemer!
齷齪的人
That's it. l want you out of this house, boy.
好了  你現在給我離開這個家
-pa! -you heard the preacher.
-爸爸  -你聽到教士是怎麼說的了
You think we don't know what you're talking about...
你以為我們不知道你說'牽我的手'
...when you say ''take my hand''?
就是指'我們私奔'的意思嗎
What? lt's about holding hands.
什麼意思  只不過手拉手而已啊
You watch your mouth.
你給我閉嘴
You know who's got hands? the devil.
你知道誰才會有這種齷齪的手麼?  魔鬼
And he uses them for holding.
只有魔鬼才會有
I ain't got no room in my house for no devil's spawn.
我家裡可沒有為魔鬼準備房間
Be careful. before you say something
別這樣  你得好好考慮考慮再作決定
you regret for the rest of your days.
以免你下半輩子後悔
Like what? like ''the wrong kid died''?
後悔什麼  後悔"小孩死錯了"嗎?
Oh, no! no!
噢  不  不
Lt's okay. lt's okay, mama, settle down.
沒事的  媽媽  沒事的
Pa's right.
爸爸說的對
Springberry ain't big enough for me no more.
斯普林貝裡對我來說已經太小了
I reckon it's time for dewey cox to move on.
我想了杜威·考克斯是時候離開了
But you're only 1 4.
但你只有14歲啊
Mama, l love you.
媽媽  我愛你
But l don't need nobody.
但我不需要任何人
All l need is my music.
我只需要我的音樂
I seen my path today, and l'm gonna take it.
我已經看清了我的道路  我準備好好走下去
And someday, l'll make my masterpiece...
將來我會成為一名偉大人物的
...and you'll all be proud of me.
到時你們都會為我驕傲的
Just like you were of nate.
就像你們為內特驕傲那樣
Can l come, dewey?
我能和你一起走嗎  杜威
Of course you can, edith. you're my girlfriend.
當然可以  伊迪絲  你是我的女朋友啊
-l am? -yeah, silly.
-真的嗎  -是啊  傻瓜
I pointed at you in the audience.
我在那麼多觀眾中就指著你啊
Did you hear that? l'm dewey's 1 2-year-old girlfriend!
你們聽到了嗎  我是杜威12歲的女朋友
You're the most talented man l've ever seen in my whole life.
你是我這一生中見過的最有才華的人
And you will never get anything
從我這裡
but love and support from me...
你將得到我永遠的愛和永遠的支持
...for you and your dreams the rest of my life.
支持你和你的夢想
Well, then, go on. get out of this house.
好吧  快走  離開這個屋子
Before l cut your dreams in half
趁在我把你的夢想砍成兩半之前
like you cut mine in half.
就像你當初砍掉我對內特的希望那樣
Goodbye, pa.
再見  爸爸
Just wait till you see what happens now.
你等著  將來你會明白現在你所做的蠢事的
Here we go.
大家來吧
Ma and pa leave home all the kids get glad
爸爸媽媽出了家門  孩子們歡天喜地
You know our house's gonna jump like mad
房子瘋狂的在蹦跳  在舞蹈
We're gonna jump, li'l children, jump
孩子們  蹦起來  跳起來
We're gonna jump, li'l children mama and papa's gone
一起跳起來吧  爸爸媽媽都不在
Let's jump, jump, jump jump, jump, jump
蹦起來  跳起來  蹦起來  跳起來
Play it for me, daddy!
夥計  音樂
That's a sexy look right there.
多性感的舞蹈
Oh, l like it, l like it.
太棒了  太漂亮了
Let's jump, jump, jump jump, jump, jump
蹦起來  跳起來  蹦起來  跳起來
We're gonna jump, li'l children mama and papa's gone
大家一起跳起來吧  爸爸媽媽都不在
You know what l'm saying.
你知道我的意思
Let's take them home, fellas.
夥計們  帶她們回家吧
We're gonna jump, li'l children mama and papa's gone
大家一起跳起來吧  爸爸媽媽都不在
Yeah, baby. wrap it up right there.
夥計  把那裡弄好
I'm gonna take one of them home tonight.
今晚我要帶他們其中一個回家
My name is bobby shad and these are the bad men.
我叫鮑比·夏德  這是我的壞男樂隊
We gonna take a break, then we be right back...
讓我們休息一會  之後我們再一起...
...to rock till the morning light, all right?
...唱到天明  好嗎
Mr. shad! mr. shad! wow, that was really great.
夏德先生  夏德先生  真是太棒了
Hey, l play a little guitar. lf you ever need--
我會彈一點吉它  如果你需要...
-dewey! -yes, sir?
-杜威!  -是的  先生
I pay you to mop, not bother the band.
我花錢是讓你來拖地  不是去騷擾樂隊的
My customers come to dance erotically,
我的顧客是來跳情慾舞的
and they need a clean floor to do it on!
把地板給我去擦乾淨
Do your job or l'll find somebody who will.
要麼幹活  要麼就走人
Yes, sir.
知道了  先生
Lonesome blues
寂寞布魯斯
Dewey, will you cut out that racket?
杜威  別吵了好不好
l'm trying to feed your child!
我在幫你喂孩子呢
How am l supposed to make it as a famous musician
如果不練習的話
if l don't practice?
我將來怎麼能成為著名歌手呢
Will you stop talking about that music?
你能不能不要談音樂了
But it's my dream, baby.
但這是我的夢想啊  寶貝
I am tired of hearing about your dreams, dewey cox.
我已經對你的夢想感到厭倦了  杜威·考克斯
You are a selfish dickhole.
你這個自私鬼
Daddy said if we move home,
爸爸說如果我們搬回家
he could give you a job at the slaughterhouse.
他就會給你在屠宰場找份工作
You can make an honest living.
你就會過得很安定的
Wouldn't have to hang your head in shame,
不用因為羞愧而低著頭走路
walking around like a failure.
像個失敗者一樣
I think l'm doing okay for a 15-year-old
作為一個15歲就要攜妻帶子的人
with a wife and a baby.
我已經做的很好了
But, sweetheart...
但是  寶貝
...l thought you liked working
我以為你以前很喜歡
at the slaughterhouse for my daddy.
在我爸爸的屠宰場做事的
I did.
我以前是很喜歡
You got a real talent for this, boy.
孩子  你在這方面很有天份
Someday this is all gonna be yours.
總有一天你就成為這的主人了
It's just, as much as l loved it, edith, l want more than that.
伊迪絲  我愛這些  但我想要更多的
Ain't no musician ever made no money, dewey.
音樂家是賺不到錢的  杜威
What? of course they do. plenty of them do.
什麼  當然會的  他們都賺得到錢
Name one.
舉個例子
-slim whitman. -who the hell is slim whitman?
-斯裡姆·威特曼  -誰是斯裡姆·威特曼
All right, frank sinatra.
弗蘭克·斯納特拉
Who the hell is frank sinatra?
誰是弗蘭克·斯納特拉
Edith, l am starting to think...
伊迪絲  我現在覺得
...that maybe you don't believe in me.
你可能並不相信我
I do believe in you.
我當然相信你
I just know you're gonna fail.
我知道你就要遭受失敗了
-what are you talking about, edith? -what about my dreams?
-你在說什麼伊迪絲  -那我的夢想呢
Edith, l told you, l can't build you a candy house!
伊迪絲  我說過我沒法給你造一個糖果做的房子
It will fall down! the sun will melt the candy! lt won't work!
會倒塌的  太陽會把它給融化的
It will if it never rains.
如果不下雨就不會倒了
Dewey, you have got to give up your dream.
杜威  放棄你的夢想吧
Dreams don't come true.
夢想不會變成現實的
I am gonna make this dream come true.
我會讓這個夢想成真的
Nobody ever said it's gonna be easy.
沒人說過這很容易
It's hard.
這是很難的
It ain't easy to walk to the top of a mountain.
登上頂峰總是很難的
It's a long, hard walk.
這是一段艱苦的旅程
It's a rocky road.
遍佈荊棘的道路
But l plan on walking.
但我還是決定前行
Oh, l'm gonna walk.
我要拚搏
Hard.
努力
I will walk hard.
我永不止步
Walk hard.
永不止步
I got a full house coming tonight.
今晚全場滿座
If bobby shad can't play l need to find someone who can.
如果鮑比·夏德不能表演  那給我找個能表演的
I'm fine. l can play through the pain.
我沒事  我能忍住
Should've thought before
你應該想到
you punched your landlord and got laryngitis.
在你嗓子發炎之前  要事先通知你的老闆
I guess there's no music tonight.
我想今晚的演出要砸了
Bullhickey! people come here to dance erotically!
該死的  人們來這裡是為了跳情慾舞的
I ain't got no music, l ain't got no nightclub.
沒有了音樂  我就沒有了夜總會
Excuse me.
打擾一下
I play a little.
我也會一點
I don't know how to tell you this, boy.
我不知道該怎麼和你說  孩子
You're white. this crowd will eat you alive.
你是白人  這些人會把你生吃了的
I been watching mr. shad every night. l know all the songs.
我每晚都看著夏德先生表演  我會唱他的所有歌曲
It'll be the same show.
這沒什麼兩樣的
It'll be just like bobby shad and the bad men,
這和鮑比和他的壞男組合一樣的
only it'll be me tonight.
只是今晚換成了我
This is crazy.
太瘋狂了
But l ain't got no other choice.
但我也沒有其他選擇
I don't mean to put more pressure on you, boy.
我並不是想給你更大的壓力  孩子
The suits from the record company just got here.
那些穿制服的唱片公司的人就在那裡
Oh, okay.
好的
Scared?
緊張嗎
-a little. -well, you should be.
-有一點  -對  你當然會緊張
Those jews control show business.
那些猶太人控制著娛樂界
Just lay it down exactly like bobby does.
像鮑比以前那樣表演就可以了
Good evening. we're bobby shad and the bad men.
晚上好  我們是鮑比·夏德的壞男孩樂隊
l'm dewey cox.
我叫杜威·考克斯
Bobby shad couldn't be here tonight
鮑比·夏德今晚不能來了
so l'm gonna do his show for you.
所以由我來為你們表演
And l hope you enjoy it.
希望你們能夠喜歡
This first song we're fitting to do is....
帶來的第一首歌是
Well, it's about....
是關於...
It's about when your woman catches you.
關於你的女人追逐你的歌
You know, she catches you running around town...
她在整座城市中奔跑  在所有的陌生人中
...getting into all kinds of strange.
她追上了你
This is racially insensitive.
白人總是反應遲鈍
And she says
她說
"son, get your lazy, two-timing,negro ass up out of here."
'孩子  帶著你那又懶惰又虛偽的黑人屁股離開這裡'
-what's he doing? you see that?
-他在幹什麼  你看到了嗎
You got to love your negro man
你一定要愛上你的黑男人
You got to love, love
你一定要愛  愛
-ls he playing ''negro man''? -he is playing ''negro man.''
-他唱的是'黑男人'嗎  -是的  是'黑男人'
He's playing ''negro man.''
他唱的是'黑人'
From early in the morning till late at night
從清晨直到黑夜
You know I love your apples let me take a bite
我愛上了你的蘋果  請讓我嘗一口
You got to love your negro man
你一定要愛上你的黑男人
You got to love, love, love, love, love
你要愛  愛  愛  愛...
Your negro man
你的黑男人
Yeah, come on, dewey.
不錯  繼續  杜威
I know I treat you wrong and that ain't right
我知道我對你態度不好  這樣不對
Let me put it on you, mama and you'll feel all right
讓我給你穿上  你會感覺很棒
You got to love your negro man
你要愛你的黑男人
You got to love, love, love, love, love
你要愛愛愛愛
Your negro man
你的黑男人
Now, that's what l call winning over an audience.
那正是我所說的  征服觀眾
Go, dewey, go.
繼續  杜威  繼續
I like what you did out there tonight.
今晚你的表演我很喜歡
have you ever made a recording?
你有錄過唱片嗎
Oh, mr. l'chaim, mr. mazeltov, that's been my dream.
艾克萊姆先生  瑪澤托先生  那可一直是我的夢想
He's not the one you want. l'm the one you want.
他不是你們想要的  我才是
-l think he's the one we want. -he's got a nice thing.
-我想他是  -他很有才
He's not bad with the singing
他唱歌不錯
and the playing and the shaking of the tochis.
玩起那吉他也還行
I think you've got what it takes to make it in the big time.
我想你有成為世界一流的潛質
The big time?
世界一流?
When the moon hits your eye like a big pizza pie
當月亮映在你的眼裡  好像一張大比薩餅
That's amore
那就是愛情
When the world seems to shine
當世界在發光
What the hell is this?
這算什麼東西
Pizza pie. what's in a pizza pie?
比薩餅  比薩餅裡面是什麼
Bells will ring ting-a-ling-a-ling, ting-a-ling-a-ling
鈴兒叮噹響  叮噹響
And you'll sing ''vita bella''
你將歌唱'美麗人生'
Hearts will play tippy-tippy-tay
心兒彭彭跳  彭彭跳
Please, l can't anymore.
我受不了了
That's what l was gonna say.
那正是我要說的
-that's amore -amore
-那就是愛情  -愛情
That is amore
那就是愛情
All right. hold, please. stop that. stop your singing!
好了  停下  別唱了
Stop your singing this instant, young man!
立刻停下來  年輕人
I will not have this in my studio!
我可不想錄這種歌曲
That's just a terrible, terrible...
這是個非常非常
...terrible, terrible ''that's amore.''
非常糟糕的  '那就是愛情'
Maybe it was a wrong song choice?
也許是因為選錯了歌
If you just let me play one of my songs,
如果讓我彈首我自己的曲子
I think you'll like it a whole lot better.
你會非常喜歡的
You have failed conclusively. lt's over.
你完全失敗了  結束了
And there is nothing that you can do...
不管你在這做什麼
...here in this room that can turn that around.
都不能挽回這個結論
Nothing you can do that can make up for what you did to ''that's amore.''
不管你做什麼  都不能彌補你所唱的'這就是愛情'
well, my mother liked it a whole lot.
我母親很喜歡
your mother was wrong.
你母親錯了
L was willing to open my mind...
我很樂意敞開心扉
...because these jewish gentlemen brought you in here.
因為你是這些猶太紳士們帶來的
They usually have good taste.
他們的鑒賞力很不錯
And now here you are in front of me pretending you can sing.
而現在你在我面前假裝一副會唱歌的樣子
And l have to say that today...
我不得不說
...your performance has shaken my belief in the jewish people.
今天你的表演  讓我開始動搖對猶太人的信任
Well, there's nothing l would like more, sir...
我很願意去
...than to restore your faith in judaism,
恢復你對猶太人的信任
if you could just give me that shot.
只要你能給我一次機會
But l'll tell you, you have failed so far...
我告訴你  你已經失敗了
...and if somehow you are able to sing a song now...
如果你想再唱一首的話
...bringing these boys together you haven't even met...
就帶上這些你素未謀面的人
...and make something so personal, so new...
彈些非常個性  新穎的作品
...that the whole world takes notice...
能令世界為之注目的作品
...and that your life is never the same again....
令以後你的生活不再像從前一樣的作品
But l'm telling you right now, l don't think it's going to happen.
但我告訴你  這不會發生的
Wait, wait, wait. we're here already.
等等  我們已經在這裡了
what could it possibly hurt?
再彈一曲有何關係呢
L'chaim, l'll do it for you. but just one more song.
艾克萊姆  看在你的面子上  但就一首歌
All right.
好的
All right, son. l'm gonna give you 15 more seconds.
好了  孩子  我再給你15秒
Thank you, sir. l hope you won't regret it.
謝謝你  先生  你不會後悔的
Dewey, we don't know this song.
杜威  我們不知道這首歌
You just follow me.
跟著我就行了
I don't know.
不知道
Walk hard
永不止步
Hard
永不
Down life's rocky road
踏在  崎嶇的人生路上
Walk bold
步伐勇敢
Hard
堅定
That's my creed
這是我的信念
My code
我的準則
I been scorned and slandered and ridiculed too
我被輕蔑過  誹謗過  嘲笑過
Had to struggle every day my whole life through
每天的生活  掙扎著
Seen my share of the worst that the world can give
看著世界扔給我的爛攤子
But I still got a dream and a burnin' rage to live
但我帶著夢想與狂暴繼續活著
Walk hard
永不止步
Hard
永不
Here is america's new hit song 'walk hard''...
這首是美國新榜歌曲  永不止步
...recorded just 35 minutes ago by dewey cox.
就在35分鐘前由杜威·考克斯剛錄製完成
Hard
永不
Though they say
雖然他們說
You're not the one
你不是這塊料
Even if you've been told time and time again
即使反反覆覆地訴說
That you're always gonna lose and never gonna win
你將永遠失敗  不會勝利
You gotta keep that vision in your mind's eye
你要將那意志刻在腦中
When you're standin' on top of a mountain high
站在山頂的最高峰
He walks so hard.
他的步伐真堅定
How do l walk, boys?
我的步伐怎麼樣
Hard
堅定
When I meet my maker on my dying day
當我在末日之時看見上帝
I'm gonna look him in the eye and by god, I'll say
我將看著他的眼睛說
I gave my word and my word was good
我向你保證
I took it in the face and I walked as hard as I could
我信以為真  我永不止步
Oh, hey, shorty. hello, my darling.
嘿  矮子  你好  親愛的
L sang a song at a circus in new jersey.
我在新澤西州的馬戲團唱了首歌
They said, ''we'll give you 5 grand.''
他們說  我們給你五千美元
L said, ''no, you won't. you'll give me that giraffe.''
我說  不必  你給我那長頸鹿
-and they did. they gave it right to me. -that is one beautiful giraffe.
-他們就答應了  立馬給了我  -這長頸鹿真漂亮
Thank you.
謝謝
It'll just be a few weeks, edith.
伊迪絲  我就離開幾周而已
Who's gonna help me take care of the children?
誰來幫我照看孩子
Dewey, you have got to give up this dream.
杜威  你必須放棄這夢想
You're never gonna make it. give it up, dewey.
你不可能達到目標的  放棄吧  杜威
What are you talking about? l got a number one hit on the radio.
你說什麼呢  我的歌在廣播裡排行第一呢
I'm playing my music for people who wanna hear me.
我在為我的粉絲彈奏著音樂
It's everything we always wanted, edith.
伊迪絲  這是我們一直想要的
I never get to see you anymore. your kids never get to see you.
我將永遠見不到你  你的孩子也是
I don't know how to tell you this.
我不知道該怎麼說
I'm gonna miss some things, okay?
我會錯過一些事情  好嗎
I'm gonna miss some birthdays and some christenings.
我將錯過生日  一些洗禮儀式
I'm gonna miss some births, period ok£¿
孩子的出生  紀念日 I'm gonna miss some births, period ok？
Unrealistic to think l'm gonna be here every time you have a baby.
也不可能  你生孩子我就要待在這兒
But aren't you happy? you have a beautiful new home.
你不高興嗎  你有了漂亮的新家
All your fancy new clothes and your monkey and your giraffe.
所有你夢想的衣服  你的猴子和長頸鹿
Look, what else you need?
你還要什麼
How about l get you a crow that could talk?
要不給你一隻會說話的烏鴉
And l'll teach him phrases that l say. 'good morning, honey.''
我會教他說  寶貝  早上好
but it'll be a little crow talking.
但偶爾會說些鳥語
this ain't about no exotic pets!
我要的不僅僅是這些奇異寵物
It's about love, you stupid piece of shit.
是愛情  你這該死的蠢蛋
-dewey. -edith!
-杜威  -伊迪絲
Don't you go in the bathroom.
別進浴室
Edith, please.
伊迪絲  求你了
Mama said there's a lot of evil on the road.
媽媽說巡迴旅途上會有很多魔鬼
Temptations.
很多誘惑
They'll make a man do evil things.
它們會驅使人們幹壞事
Edith, that is ridiculous. Is that what this is all about?
伊迪絲  那是無稽之談  這就是你要說的嗎
There ain't no evil out there.
外面沒有什麼魔鬼
Come on, now, cupcake, open the door.
別這樣  打開門
Edith.
伊迪絲
My beautiful, beautiful, beautiful angel.
我漂漂亮亮的天使
You know how much l love you.
你知道我是多愛你
You and this fast-growing family of ours...
你和這個迅速成長的家庭
...is the only thing that matters to me.
才是我最關心的事情
You understand that?
你懂嗎
Heck, life without you would be like no life at all.
沒有你的人生將毫無意義
Like no life at all.
將毫無意義
Where's a pencil? where's a pencil?
筆在哪?  筆在哪?
Dewey!
杜威!
Hello, baby!
你好  寶貝!
Yeah, this is the big bopper speaking.
是啊  我是鮑普大哥啊
Oh, you sweet thing.
你個小甜心
Do l what?
我會什麼?
Will l what?
我能什麼?
Oh, baby, you know what l like.
哦寶貝  你知道我喜歡什麼
Chantilly lace and a pretty face and a ponytail
香蒂伊蕾絲花邊和漂亮臉蛋  還有馬尾辮
How are we supposed to follow that?
我們怎麼繼續下去啊?
Don't worry, dewey, you'll do great.
杜威  別擔心  你會出彩的
-thanks, buddy holly. -lf you don't, l'll pick it back up.
-謝謝你  巴蒂·候力  -如果你不行  我會幫你頂上
-you got nothing to worry about. -oh, thank you.
-你不必擔心  -哦  謝謝
I really like that ''walk hard'' song.
我很喜歡你那首  永不止步
Oh, thanks.
謝謝
I like that ''peggy sue'' song.
我喜歡你那首'致佩吉·蘇'
It's my favorite buddy holly song.
我最喜歡的
Thanks, dewey. l'm awful proud of that one.
謝謝  杜威  那首歌我的確是相當自豪
Man, l'm awful nervous, buddy holly.
天啊  巴蒂·候力  我是相當緊張
Dewey, you'll be fine, or my name's not buddy holly.
杜威  沒事的  我的名字不是巴蒂·候力
Hey guys,change of plans.
夥計們  計劃變了
elvis wants to get out of here early. he's hungry.
艾維斯想早些走  他餓了
So we'll change the order. after the big bopper, it's buddy holly...
所以我們改變下出場順序  鮑普大哥之後是巴蒂·候力
...then elvis presley, and then you, dewey cox.
然後艾維斯·普雷斯利  再然後是你  杜威·考克斯
So it's the big bopper...
那麼是鮑普大哥
...and then buddy holly...
然後巴蒂·候力
...and then elvis presley, and then me?
接著艾維斯·普雷斯利  再是我
Yeah. just for tonight.
對  只是今晚而已
Well, l'm just happy to be here.
能站在這裡我已經很高興了
What am l doing?
我在幹什麼?
L ain't good enough to follow elvis.
我怎麼可能接在艾維斯後面唱
What are you talking about, dewey?
杜威  你說什麼呢?
Nate. nate, is that you?
內特  是你嗎?
You can do it, dewey. l know you can.
杜威  我知道你行的
L know because l'm your brother, and l believe in you.
因為我是你兄弟  我相信你
But, hell, ain't nobody can follow elvis.
但沒人能接艾維斯唱下去
-wait, did you say elvis? -yeah.
-等等  你說艾維斯?  -是啊
Elvis presley? the king of rock 'n' roll?
艾維斯·普雷斯利嗎  貓王?
Yeah, elvis presley.
對  艾維斯·普雷斯利
He has nine number one hits.
他有九首單曲上過金曲榜
Nate, l understand that.
內特  我知道
He has 50 million fans.
他有五千萬名粉絲
I'm aware of that, nate.
我知道  我正想辦法
I'm trying to figure it out that's why l'm out here.
所以我才出來了
I'm having a crisis.
我這下尷尬了
Holy shit.
該死
Dewey! the big fella's on his final encore. are you ready?
杜威  大明星快唱完了  你準備好了嗎
Yeah. l'm ready.
是的  我準備好了
Elvis!
艾維斯
Ladies.
女士們
Dang, elvis presley, you didn't have to rile them up like that.
艾維斯·普雷斯利  你沒必要讓他們如此興奮
What, now?
什麼?
-no, l'm-- -excuse me, what?
-不  我...  -對不起  你說什麼?
L'm just saying, we gotta follow that and--
我是說  我們還要接著唱下去呢
Well, sometimes you have to go all out
當你成為搖滾之王的時候
when you're the king you cant help.
你總是忍不住要全力以赴
Because there's only one man who's the king.
因為只有一個搖滾之王
God picks him, hand-plucks him.
上帝的寵兒  親手將他扶起
One night, god looked down at
一晚  上帝俯視著
all the millions and millions of people, man...
成千上萬的臣民
...and he decided which one was the best, and it was me.
決定著誰是唯一的寵兒  那就是我
He plucked me from all those millions and millions of people, man.
他從成千上萬的人中將我挑出
-yeah. -listen to this, right now.
-是啊  -你給我聽著
There's two things you need to know. -i'm the king and no. two is
兩件事情你要知道  我是搖滾之王  第二件事
Look out, man! look at that coming at you. you see that?
注意了  看到剛才那招了嗎
Lt's called karate and only two kinds of people know it.
那叫空手道  只有兩種人懂
The chinese and the king.
中國人和貓王
And one of them is me.
其中一個便是我
You're the king.
你是貓王
On to memphis,
在孟菲斯
they want a nice little honey and a little bit of june bug.
人們想要來點蜂蜜和綠花金魚
-yeah? -yeah....
-是嗎  -是啊
Come on, man....
來吧
Look out, man!
小心了  夥計
Well, thanks, elvis.
謝謝了   艾維斯
Let's go. come on, mama.
來  我們走
What the fuck was he talking about?
他TMD剛才說什麼呢?
How y'all doing? my name's dewey cox.
你們好嗎?  我叫杜威·考克斯
And, well, looks like l got some proving myself to do.
看來現在我得做些事情來證明我自己
Sam.
薩姆
Walk hard
永不止步
Hard
永不
Down life's rocky road
踏在  崎嶇的人生路上
Wow, great playing, boys.
大家彈得不錯啊
The fillies love you, dewey.
杜威  那些姑娘們愛死你了
If l wasn't married man with a good head on my shoulders,
如果我不是個頭腦清醒的已婚男人
I don't know what l'd do.
真不知道該怎麼辦
You gotta get back out there. they are going crazy.
你得回到台上去  他們要發瘋了
Let me splash some water on my face i'll be right back
我去洗把臉  馬上回來
Okay. hurry up!
好的  快點啊
Golly, that rock 'n' roll.
哇靠  那搖滾真是
-get out of here, dewey. -what are y'all doing in here?
-杜威  出去  -你們在這幹什麼
We're smoking reefer, and you don't want no part of this shit.
吸大麻  你不會想要這鬼東西的
You're smoking reefers?
吸食大麻?
Of course we are. can't you smell it?
當然了  你沒聞出來嗎?
No, sam, l can't.
不  我聞不出來
Come on, dewey, join the party.
來吧  杜威  加入我們
No, dewey, you don't want this. get out of here!
杜威  你不會想要的  離開這
I don't want no hangover. I can't get no hangover.
我不想要宿醉  我不能宿醉
It doesn't give you a hangover.
它不會讓你宿醉的
Will l get addicted to it or something?
會讓我上癮嗎?
It's not habit-forming.
這不會讓你上癮的
Oh, okay, well....
哦  那行
I don't know. l don't wanna overdose on it.
我不知道  我不想過度吸食
You can't od on it.
你也過度不了
It's not gonna make me wanna have sex, is it?
不會讓我想做愛吧
It makes sex even better.
這比性愛更爽
Sounds kind of expensive.
聽上去挺貴的
It's the cheapest drug there is.
這是最便宜的毒品
You don't want it.
你不會想要的
I think l kind of want it.
我有點想要
Okay, but just this once. come on in.
好吧  就這一次  進來吧
-what do l do? -like this.
-我該怎麼做  -這樣
Oh, my.
哦  爽
Hey, listen, folks.
各位聽眾
I'd like to play a song l wrote for a very special lady.
我要彈首歌  寫給一位特殊女士的歌
I'm talking about mrs. dewey cox.
我是說我的妻子
Oh, my darling'
哦  親愛的
I have a perfect life
我擁有個完美的人生
You are the perfect wife
你是我完美的妻子
I don't know why
不知為何
I sit and cry
我坐著哭泣
And now I miss you so
我現在是如此地思念你
Please don't let me go
請別離開我
I make mistakes and that is true
我確實時常犯著錯誤
At least I learn each time I do
至少每次我都得到了教訓
Here, have some of this.
嘗嘗這個
Darling, you must believe
親愛的  你要相信
I could never leave you if I tried
我決不能離開你
A life without you
沒有你的人生
Is no life at all
有何意義
Oh, my darlin'
哦  親愛的
Beth anne.
貝絲·安妮
Can l get that for you?
能讓我幫你拿嗎?
Thanks, dewey.
杜威  謝謝你
Tears fall in vain
徒勞的眼淚
I'm standing in the rain
我站在雨中
No matter how I feel
不管我的感覺怎樣
I never seem to know what's real
我從沒看清事實的真相
So sharpen up your knives
磨亮你的刀叉吧
-can l get that for you? -thanks, dewey.
-我能幫你提嗎?  -杜威  謝謝你
L'm a bad horse.
我是匹賤馬
Phil, can l get that for you?
菲利普  我能幫你提嗎?
Thanks, dewey.
杜威  謝謝你
Darling, you must believe
親愛的  你要相信
I could never leave you if I tried
我決不能離開你
Phil? what happened?
菲利普  怎麼回事?
A life without you
沒有你的人生
Is no life at all
將有何意義
Well, the tour's going real great, baby.
寶貝  這次巡演真的很棒
Yeah, we're having a real nice time.
我們過得很愉快
Yeah, the boys have been playing great...
大家都表演得很好
...and the audiences have been just wonderful, so....
觀眾們都很不錯  所以...
-when you coming home? -soon, baby, real soon.
-你什麼時候回來?  -很快  寶貝  很快了
We gotta hit the major markets in the northeast,
我們要進軍東北地區主要市場
chicago, detroit--
芝加哥  底特律
Dewey, could you shut up?
杜威  能閉嘴不?
I'm trying to have sex with these women down here.
我正和這些女人做愛
Who's that?
那是誰?
Oh, that's sam.
哦  是薩姆
-he's just looking for his drumsticks. -howdy.
-他在找他的鼓槌  -你好
Excuse me.
對不起
Anyway, you don't wanna hear about this boring stuff.
總之  你不會想聽這些無聊瑣事的
how was your day?
你過得怎麼樣?
Oh, you know, just taking care of the kids.
你知道  就是照看孩子
Went down to wilson's market the other day to pick up some milk.
前幾天去威爾森超市買了點牛奶
Completely out of milk.
牛奶全部喝光了
I had to go all the way down to peach street.
我不得不沿著桃樹街一路走下來
-i hate going down there. -oh, brother. can you believe it?
-我討厭去那  -哦  難以置信
-yes, bert? -hey, dewey.
-伯特  什麼事  -嘿  杜威
-you want a cup of coffee? -no, thank you.
-要喝咖啡嗎  -不  謝謝
Will you give me a minute? l'm on the phone here.
等一等  我在打電話
-who's that? -that's bert, my roadie.
-那是誰  -那是伯特  樂隊管理員
Just wants to know if l want any coffee or anything like that.
問我要不要咖啡什麼的
Dewey, there's a distance growing between us,
杜威  我感覺我們間的距離越來越遠
I feel, and l don't like it.
這讓我很難受
Oh, now, that is crazy talk, edith.
迪絲  別說瞎話了
You know l'm just the same old dewey.
我還是原來那個杜威
-hey, dewey. -yes, bert?
-嘿  杜威  -伯特  什麼事?
You seen my sandals?
你看見我的拖鞋了嗎?
I don't know. I'm talking to my wife, bert.
不知道  我在和我老婆打電話
Baby, there's somebody at the door. l gotta go.
寶貝  有人在敲門  我得掛了
Can I call when I get to new jersey?
到了新澤西我再打給你  好嗎?
Okay. bye, dewey.
那好  拜拜
-i love you. -all right.
-我愛你  -好的
-i love you. -l love you.
-我愛你  -我愛你
-you're never gonna make it, okay? -okay, bye.
-你不會成功的  明白嗎?  -知道了  再見
Bye.
再見
-pa. -dewey.
-爸  -杜威
What are you doing here?
你來這幹嗎?
It's about your mama.
是關於你媽媽的
Ma? what about her? ls she okay?
媽媽  她怎麼了?  她沒事吧?
We better step out into the hall.
我們還是到大廳裡聊
-what happened? -l'll tell you what happened.
-發生什麼事了?  -我來告訴你是怎麼回事
We were readying for bed
當時我們準備睡覺的時候
when your song comes on the radio.
在廣播裡聽到了你的歌
It's dewey!
是杜威
Your son is talented. you should be proud.
你兒子很有才華  你應該為此而驕傲
Well, l must admit, it is kind of catchy.
不得不承認  這首歌確實不錯
Dance with me, pa.
和我跳支舞吧  孩子他爹
It does make you kind of wanna move, doesn't it?
你還別說  這歌聽著確實讓人想跳跳舞
It sure does.
當然了
Maybe l have been kind of hard on little dewey.
也許我對小杜威嚴厲了一點
Maybe you have.
是啊
Be careful, ma.
小心  孩子他媽
-you all right, ma? -l'm all right.
-你沒事吧  孩子他媽  -我沒事
The vertigo, it won in the end.
暈眩癥最終把她給害死了
She lost her balance...
她失去了平衡...
...and fell out the window...
...然後跌出了窗外...
...and then the radio crushed her head?
...然後收音機砸到了她腦袋上了
While she was dancing to your song.
而且是當她在聽著你的歌跳舞的時候
I thought you should know what your music does.
我想你應該明白你那音樂幹的好事了吧
It kills people.
它能殺人
You made her happy and it killed her.
你讓她興高采烈  然後又殺了她
If nate was alive, this never would have happened.
如果內特還活著的話  這事絕對不會發生
Wrong kid died.
死錯孩子了
Damn you, god!
上帝去你媽的
How could you let my mama fall out a window?
你怎麼能讓我媽媽跌出窗戶?
And then let a radio hit her on the head?
然後又讓收音機砸在她腦袋上啊
-get out of here, dewey. -what are y'all doing in here?
-出去  杜威  -你們都在這做什麼?
Lt's called cocaine, and you don't want no part of this shit.
這叫可卡因  你不會想要染上這鬼東西的
Cocaine?
可卡因?
What's it do?
吸了它會怎麼樣?
It turns all your bad feelings into good feelings.
它會讓你所有的痛苦哀愁全都煙消雲散
It's a nightmare.
很可怕啊
I'm thinking maybe l'd like to try me some of that cocaine.
我想我需要來嘗嘗這可卡因
When I meet my maker on my dying day
當我死前  我看見了我的父親
Look him in the eye and by god I'll say
看著他的眼睛我會對他說
I gave my word and my word was good
我做出了一個善意的許諾
I took it in the face and I walked as hard as I could
把話丟給你我轉身就走
Walk hard walk hard, hard, hard
永不止步  堅定步伐  永不  永不
Walk hard, hard, hard walk....
永不止步  永不  永不止步
All right, again. faster.
很好  再來一次  再快一點
This is crazy, dewey.
杜威  這太瘋狂了
ain't nobody gonna wanna listen to music like this.
沒人會要聽這樣的音樂的
Standing there playing as fast as you can...
站在那裡發了瘋似的拚命彈奏...
...singing like some sort of punk.
...像個瘋子似的大喊大叫
Don't you dare try to stifle me.
你竟然敢和我唱反調
Whose band is this anyway, you cocksucker!
這到底是誰的樂隊  你們這些垃圾
I'll punch you in the mouth!
我會打得你滿地找牙
Oh, god. l'm sorry, dave.
我的天  對不起  戴維
No, l didn't mean that.
我不是故意的
Just with my mama dying and all, l'm just all twisted up inside.
我媽媽去世的事讓我心如亂麻
Mr. cox?
考克斯先生
I heard you were looking for a new backup singer.
我聽說您在為你新的二重唱
for your new duet.
尋覓合作歌手
You heard right.
沒錯
I was wondering if you might like to give me a try.
您能否給我一個機會試試
I reckon l might.
可以試試
I've been singing in my church choir since l was a girl.
我從小就在教堂唱詩班裡唱歌
I like the sound of that.
我喜歡教堂裡的音樂的
Darlene madison.
我叫戴琳·麥迪遜
Dewey cox.
我是杜威·考克斯
Hello, darlene.
你好  戴琳
Hello, mr. cox.
你好  考克斯先生
You ready to sing one?
準備好一起唱一曲了嗎?
I'm always ready.
隨時奉陪
Well, all right.
好吧
In my dreams you're blowin' me
我的夢中  你的親吻
Some kisses
讓我沉迷
That's one of my favorite things to do
那是我也最陶醉的事情
You and I could go down
你和我可以一起
In history
穿越歷史
That's what I'm prayin' to do with you
那是我日夜祈禱和你做的事
Let's duet
讓我們在一起
In ways that make us feel good
一起盡情享受
And make that sacred sound
唱出那神聖的歌曲
Dewey cox! l am not that kind of woman.
杜威·考克斯  我不是那種隨便的女人
-all right. -well...
-好吧  -不過...
...that doesn't mean that we still can't be friends.
...這並不意味著我們不能做朋友了
Okay.
好吧
Well, then, here's to us being great friends.
那樣的話  為我們成為摯友來一個吧
I can't! we're friends!
不行  我們是朋友
I'm gonna beat off
我會打敗
All my demons
所有魔鬼
That's what lovin' jesus' all about
那是偉大的上帝存在的原因
Lookin' in your eyes I start believin'
看著你的眼睛我開始相信
Let's bring this whisper to a shout
就讓我們用高喊來替代耳語
Let's duet
讓我們在一起
In ways that make us feel good
一起盡情享受
Put two and two together
兩顆心在一起
Perfect harmony we've found
我們會聽到完美的和諧之音
We know it's only natural
相信這是最自然不過的事
Let's duet
就讓我們在一起
I just wanna make out
我只是想弄清
What you're sayin'
你在說什麼
Read my lips it's what you're lookin' for
看著我的雙唇你就會讀懂
Here I am a-sneakin' up behind you
我在你身後偷偷摸摸跟蹤
You can always come in my back door
我家後門隨時為你恭候
Let's duet
讓我們在一起
Darlene, these last three weeks have been so...
戴琳  這三個星期是這麼的...
...full and wonderful.
...充實而美好
We've shared so many activities together as good friends.
我們作為朋友已經在一起做過許多事情了
It's like you understand me the way nobody else ever has.
彷彿你比其他任何人都更瞭解我
I mean, if l--
我是說  如果我
-what is it, dewey? -l don't know.
-怎麼了?  杜威  -不知道
It's nothing. l'm fine.
沒事  我很好
Nothing? you look like you seen a ghost.
沒事?  瞧你  像見了鬼似的
I got a lot of pain in me, darlene.
我的內心深處有很多痛楚  戴琳
You should know that.
你應該知道的
Where does all that pain come from, dewey?
是什麼給你帶來這麼多痛苦呢?  杜威
Did you ever have something that you really loved...
你曾經是否有過你最摯愛的東西
...that you accidentally...
然後被你失手
...killed, or hurt in some way, with a machete?
...用一把砍刀給殺害了
-no. -no, me neither.
-沒有  -沒有  我也沒有
wouldn't that be terrible?
那樣簡直太可怕了
how would you live with yourself?
這怎麼可能還有臉活下去?
I know, right? exactly.
是啊  我也這麼想
Darling darlene
親愛的 戴琳
I'm in love with you I'm havin' fun with you
我愛上了你  和你在一起我很快樂
I'm in love with you I'm on the run with you
我愛上了你  我要和你私奔
I'm in love with you and I'll be one with you one day
我愛上了你  總有一天我們會合二為一
Thanks for letting me sleep in your bunk, dewey.
謝謝你讓我睡你的床上  杜威
Gotta sleep somewhere, right?
總得找個地方睡覺  不是嗎
-dewey, l can't. -l know. l know.
-杜威  不行  -我明白
We both know that the sexual tension between us is palpable.
我們都瞭解  咱倆隨時都有可能發生性關係
Don't you know
難道你不知道
that l wrestle with the same temptations you do?
我和你一樣也在抵禦著誘惑嗎?
I know l shouldn't be saying this to you, dewey...
我知道我不該和你說這些  杜威
...because we're not married and we're just friends...
因為我們沒有結婚  我們只是朋友
...but sometimes l lie awake at night
但有時候晚上我躺在床上
aching for a man's touch.
總渴望著一個男人的愛撫
And by ''a man's touch,''
我說的男人的愛撫
l mean a penis in my vagina.
意思是把小弟弟放進我的洞洞裡
It's just so silly.
這簡直太傻了
Oh, that's so silly.
那簡直是太傻了
-well, we better get some sleep. -okay.
-我們還是早點睡吧  -好的
Take my hand, dewey.
握著我的手  杜威
Let's promise to never, ever give in to our lesser desires.
我們保證不向那些愚昧的慾望所屈服
After all, we're not married.
不管怎樣  我們還不是夫妻
I'm ready for sex.
我準備好和你上床了
I been waiting for this for so long.
我等這一天等了好久了
Me too.
我也是
From the moment l laid eyes on you.
從我見你的那一刻起
Dewey, l'm nervous.
杜威  我有點緊張
Don't worry, angel. l'll show you the ways of love.
別擔心  小天使  我來教你什麼叫做真正的愛
Whoops-a-daisy.
一朵雛菊
Oh, dewey.
哦  杜威
Surprise!
驚喜
Edith!
伊迪絲
-who are you? -l'm his wife, that's who l am.
-你是誰?  -我是誰  我是他的老婆
No, you're not. l'm his--
你不是  我才是他的--
-good lord, you're already married? -l can explain.
-上帝啊  你早就結婚了  -聽我解釋
Explain to her? you should explain to me.
幹嘛向她解釋?  你應該向我解釋才對
I am the mother of your children.
你那一堆孩子一輩子都是喝著我的奶
-lt's not what it looks like. -You have children?
-絕對不是這樣的  -你都有孩子了?
It's not what it looks like.
絕對不是這樣的
Not what it looks like to me, or not what it looks like to her?
什麼不是這樣的  和我不是還是和她不是?
It's gotta be the way it looks like to at least one of us.
至少得有一個不是
We're married.
我們結婚了
I did the right thing.
我做了我該做的
lt's not like we're not married.
我們又不是沒有結婚
If you're married, you can't get married again.
如果你已經結過婚了  就不能再結了
I know, l know, and that was wrong, but it's just....
我知道我知道  這樣不對  可是...
We were such good friends.
我們是如此要好的朋友
You told me about that dream where you were licking my balls...
你曾經告訴我你夢見給我口交...
...and that seemed like a signal, and....
...我以為是一種暗示  然後我就...
I forgot.
把你給忘了
I'm leaving you, dewey cox, and l will see you in court!
我要走了  杜威·考克斯  咱們法庭上見
No, edith! don't go!
不  伊迪絲  別走
Oh, well. she's gone now.
好了  她走了
I'm leaving too. you got the order of things all backwards.
我也要走了  你把一切都弄得不成樣子
Darlene, don't go!
戴琳  別走
Edith, don't go either!
伊迪絲  你也別走
I made a mistake. l made a terrible mistake.
我錯了  大錯特錯了
Edith! edith! edith!
伊迪絲  伊迪絲  伊迪絲
leave me alone, dewey.
別纏著我  杜威
l never meant no harm to you.
我從來沒有想過要傷害你
Edith. cupcake.
伊迪絲  小乖乖
Baby, you don't know what it's like out there on the road.
寶貝  你根本不瞭解我在外面闖蕩的感覺
It's lonely out there.
時常都會寂寞
Edith, l can't be alone.
伊迪絲  我無法忍受寂寞
Maybe you should've thought of that
在你重婚之前
before you got double married.
你就應該想到這一點
Is that what this is about?
你就為這個鬧個不停嗎?
Don't you stand there and judge me like
不要站在那批判我
l'm some kind of criminal.
好像我是個罪犯似的
You are a criminal. this is illegal, dewey.
你就是罪犯  重婚是犯法的  杜威
What do you mean?
什麼意思
It's illegal to be married to two people at the same time, dewey.
同時和兩個人結婚時違法的  杜威
What about if you're famous? ls that--?
那如果是名人呢  那樣能不能...
You never done nothing you shouldn't have done?
難道你就沒有做過不該做的事嗎
What have l ever done to you?
我做什麼錯事了?
You woke up in the middle of the night and drank the milk.
你半夜起床把牛奶都喝光了
I got up to have my cornflakes, there's none left.
害我早上起來沒有牛奶來泡我的麥片
Dewey, you cheated on me!
杜威  你背叛了我
So l'm a cheater,
就因為我是個叛徒
but you can just drink up all the milk.
你就可以心安理得地把牛奶喝光了
Okay. all right, that's fine, l get it.
好吧  我明白了
you're innocent, and l'm guilty.
你是清白的  我有罪
Guilty as charged.
罪有應得
Don't you dare write a song right now, dewey!
你現在敢去寫歌  杜威
You know what? go ahead. take the children. l don't care.
走吧  把孩子都帶走  我無所謂
All l need is my music.
我只要我的音樂
I don't need you.
我不需要你
And l don't need you.
我也不需要你
You're just sitting there all high and mighty in your diaper.
你就會穿著尿布坐在那裡  裝得唯我獨尊
If anything, you need me. you're a baby.
真有什麼的話  也是你需要我  你不過是個小孩
Come on, miles.
走吧  邁爾
Don't you dare take miles.
你休想把邁爾帶走
You can take the children, but you leave me my monkey.
你可以把孩子帶走  但是把我小猴子留下
Fine.
好吧
Goodbye, dewey cox.
再見  杜威·考克斯
No! no, come back.
不  不  回來
Don't leave me, edith.
伊迪絲別離開我
Don't leave me, edith.'' there's a title for a song.
伊迪絲別離開我  這句適合做歌名
That's not a bad title, but please don't leave me.
當歌名還算湊合  但求你真的別離開我
What have you done?
你都做了些什麼啊
I'm telling you, l've had it. l've had it with all this crap.
我告訴你  我受夠了  受夠了你的這些破事
You took her side every time.
你和她一模一樣
All you care about is fruit and touching yourself.
你只關心吃水果  只會自慰
well, fuck you.
去你媽的
Get out of here. you don't want no part of this.
出去  你不會要染上這東西的
what y'all doing in here?
你們都在這做什麼
we doing pills, uppers and downers.
我們在嗑藥  能讓你欲死欲僊
They're the logical next step for you.
你也快到這級別了
I want some of that shit.
給我來點嘗嘗
Good morning, your honor. may l approach the bench?
早上好  法官大人  我可以上審判台了嗎?
I don't give a damn what anyone thinks
我不在乎別人他媽的怎麼想
I stay up all night and I smoke and I drink
我徹夜不眠  喝著酒  叼著煙槍
I'm a wanted man and I'm blowin' town
我是個通緝犯  把鎮子的人都殺光
Don't waste your time tryin' to hunt me down
別浪費時間試圖捉拿我歸案
The cops are sayin' I belong behind bars
條子們要我去蹲牢房
And I'm guilty
因為我有罪
Guilty
有罪
I'm guilty as charged
罪有應得
Does dewey seem unhappy to you?
你覺得杜威是不是不開心啊?
He's changed, l tell you, he's changed.
他變了  夥計  他真的變了
That was early dewey, this is middle dewey.
之前是早年的杜威  現在是中年的杜威
Dewey, are you enjoying yourself?
杜威  你覺得的爽嗎?
What? oh, l'm sorry. l forgot you were here.
什麼?  抱歉  我忘了你在這了
Hey, dave. l like your girl better, let's switch.
戴維  我更喜歡你的妞  我們交換吧
-well, dewey, this is my wife. -oh, nice to meet you.
-杜威 這是我老婆  -很高興見到你
Well, this is kathy. kathy, this is dave.
這是凱茜  凱茜這是戴維
Come on, darling. so where you from?
來吧  親愛的  你是哪裡人啊
Hi there.
你好
Guilty
有罪
I'm guilty as charged
我罪有應得
I ain't askin' god to forgive my sins
我不祈求上帝會原諒我
Take a good look and you'll know where I've been
你只要認真看看  就能體會到我經歷的生活
I'm dancin' with the devil every night and every day
每天每夜與魔鬼共舞
People pay attention to the things that I say
人們關心我所言所語
Say
說
Hey, jerry, l'm a long-time listener
嘿  傑瑞  我是你的忠實聽眾
and a first-time caller.
不過這是我第一次打電話來
Yeah, l just wanted to say l love the show, keep it up.
我只想說我喜歡你的節目  繼續加油
Am l on the radio right now?
我的歌現在在榜上嗎?
I'm guilty as charged
我罪有應得
If you're sayin' my love is too large
如果你說我太過博愛
Then I'm guilty
我有罪
Goddamn it, this is a dark fucking period!
他媽的  這真是個黑暗時期
freeze! hands above your head.
不許動  雙手抱頭
It's not what it looks like.
不是看起來這麼回事的
I'm guilty as charged
我罪有應得
Stop!
別跑
You got me.
我被捕了
Come on, mr. cox. how about it? look here.
拜託  考克斯先生  談談感受吧  看這裡
I'm guilty as charged
我罪有應得
Cox, you got a visitor.
考克斯  有人來看你
Prison has changed me.
監獄生活改變了我
I understand the common man in a way l never did before.
我懂得了怎麼去做一個正常的人
I gotta get out of here
我得出去
so l can bring joy to the men back in here.
這樣我就能給這裡面的人帶來歡樂
But I don't wanna live with them.
但我並不想和他們住一起
Lean closer.
靠近點
I'm going to speak to you in my language...
我要用我們的語言和你說話...
...so that the guards can't understand what l'm saying.
...這樣這些守衛就聽不懂我在說什麼了
There must be something you can do.
你一定有什麼辦法把我弄出去
I'm 21 years old.
我才21歲啊
I got my whole life ahead of me....
我還有大半輩子要活呢
We think we can get you off.
我們有辦法把你弄出去
What do l have to do?
那要我做什麼
You gotta go to rehab.
你得接受戒毒治療
-''rehab''? -rehab.
-"截圖"?  -戒毒
-rehab? -oh, rehab. okay, okay, l gotcha.
-戒毒?  -哦  戒毒  明白了
Doctor! doctor!
醫生  醫生
-l'm so cold. -we need more blankets.
-我好冷  -多拿點床單來
We need more blankets.
多拿點床單來
Doctor!
醫生
-l'm so hot! -l think he has too many blankets.
-我好熱   -床單蓋太多了吧
Fewer blankets!
拿走點床單
I'm hot and cold at the same time!
我又冷又熱
He needs more blankets and he needs less blankets.
他需要多一點床單  又需要少一點床單
I'm afraid you're right.
你說的沒錯
Dewey?
杜威
My wife sends her love...
我妻子向你問好...
...asshole.
...你這混蛋
Dewey, tall and powerful
杜威  高大又威猛
Dewey, l don't know if you can hear me in there...
杜威  我不知道你能不能聽見我說話
...but the wrong kid died.
...死錯孩子了
Dewey. do you mind if we get stoned in here?
杜威 你介意我們在這裡嗑藥嗎
He can't hear you. he's gonna die anyway.
他聽不到你說話  他早晚要死的
Are you ready to go home, dewey cox?
你準備好回家了嗎?  杜威·考克斯
Darlene.
戴琳
I could never get you out of my head.
我一直無法忘記你
Me neither.
我也是
I could never stop thinking about you.
我一直都想著你
But l wasn't gonna be no home wrecker.
我之前不想做你們的第三者
Now that l'm your only wife though, it seems different.
不過現在我是你唯一的妻子了  一切都不一樣了
I'm a new man, darlene. prison and rehab have changed me.
我重新改過了  戴琳  監獄和戒毒改變了我
All these blankets have saved my life.
這些床單拯救了我
I think you're finally ready to be the man l always thought you could be.
我想你終於可以成為我想要的人了
Let me get this off.
我來把這個脫了
I love you.
我愛你
I love you too.
我也愛你
Oh, my god.
我的天啊
Oh, don't stop.
別停下來
Don't stop. don't stop, dewey.
不要停  不要停  杜威
Oh, god.
天哪
Oh, yes!
真爽
Hey, boys, have you seen dewey?
小伙子們  你們看見杜威了嗎?
I think l saw him in the barn with wavy gravy
我好像看到他和瓦維·格萊維在65620067里
I saw him by the creek talking to donovan.
我看到他和唐納凡在小溪旁
No, l think he was painting a portrait with joni mitchell.
不  我想他和喬尼·米伽在給雕像上油漆
Jerry garcia, brother, have you seen dewey?
傑瑞·格煞  你看見杜威了嗎?
L think l saw him in the study, sister darlene.
我想他在書房裡  戴琳小姐
Thanks, jerry garcia.
謝謝  傑瑞·格煞
Hey! casey, jones, watch your speed.
喂!  凱西  瓊斯  你們慢點跑
Come on, dewey. lt's almost time for dewman's cake.
快來  杜威  快到給杜門切蛋糕的時候了
All right. lt's just-- lt's hard for me to sit around at some birthday party...
知道了  但是--當我知道這世界上還有這麼多不平之事...
...when l know there's so much injustice going on in this world.
我就無法坐下來參加生日聚會
-l know. -my daddy was right.
-我知道 -我爸爸是對的
L can't spend all my time thinking about dewey cox no more.
我再也不能只想著我自己了
L've got to think about the other people.
要多考慮一些別人的事
Like your family?
比如家裡人?
No, l mean, like, people that's having injustices done to them.
沒有  我是說那些受到不公正對待的人們
Like women and midgets and such.
例如婦女和侏儒等
L mean, it's 1 966, darlene. and, baby...
現在是1966年  戴琳  聽我說...
...l'm feeling it.
...我有一種非常強烈的感覺
L know. the '60s are an important and exciting time.
我知道  這是一個非常重要和振奮人心的時代
Aren't they? lt's like there's something happening here.
不是嗎? 有些偉大的事情正在發生
And what it is ain't exactly...
而且不是那麼...
...obvious.
...明顯
L have to try to help people with my music.
我要用我的歌聲來幫助他們
Some people are saying that your new music sounds a lot like bob dylan.
有人說你的新音樂風格很像鮑勃·迪倫
Well, maybe bob dylan sounds a lot like me.
也可以說他的音樂風格很像我的
How come nobody
怎麼沒有人去問
Why you sound so much like dewey cox?''
鮑勃·迪倫為什麼他的音樂風格和我這麼相似?
Mailboxes drip like lampposts in the twisted birth canal of the coliseum
郵箱像體育場邊上的路燈一樣閃亮
Rimjob fairy teapots mask the temper tantrum
魔法壺使人平和
Oh, say can you see 'em?
你察覺到這些了嗎?
Stuffed cabbage is the darling of the laundromat
塞得滿滿的行李箱就是洗衣店裡的
The mouse with the overbite explained how the rabbits were ensnared
老鼠在解釋兔子怎樣鑽進了圈套
What the hell is this song about?
這到底是什麼歌?
L have no idea.
我不懂
You guys are idiots. this song is very deep.
你們太笨了  這首歌對於你們來說太深奧
Inside the three-eyed monkey within inches of his toaster-oven life
三眼猴過著如火如荼的生活
What do your parents think about your protest songs?
你的父母對你的抗議歌怎麼看?
What do your parents think about my protest songs, mr. time magazine?
那你父母對我的抗議歌是怎麼看的  《時代》先生?
All the elevator buttons
電梯上的按紐
So incredibly high
都高不可及
I stand today for the midget
我為侏儒們出頭
Half the size of a regular guy
他們不比普通人的身高
Let me hold you, little man
讓我幫助你們
As the parade passes by
遊行
We'll make believe you can fly
我們相信你們可以飛翔
You shout for me to put you down
你讓我放你下來
But I'm marching today for your cause
但是我要繼續遊行
I'm banging the drum your big day will come
大聲高歌  屬於你們的時代就要來臨
When they remake the wizard of oz
馬上就要來
So let me hold you, midget man
讓我舉著你
Pretend that you're flying in space
讓你飛翔在空中
So the dog will stop licking your face
再也不會有狗來舔你的臉
Sing with me!
一起來!
Sing it!
一起唱!
Mr. cox, why are you going to lndia?
考克斯先生  你為什麼要去印度?
Well, l'm searching for something, if you must know.
如果你一定要知道  我只能說我在尋找些東西
L'm fixing to do some meditating with the maharishi.
我要去印度和法師一起去深思
And dewey cox needs lndia right now...
杜威·考克斯現在需要去印度...
...and, heck, l reckon lndia needs dewey cox too.
...我想印度也需要杜威·考克斯
Only through meditation can we begin to understand our role.
只能通過深思我們才能明白自己
We're nothing but grains of sand.
我們只不過是塵世裡的一粒沙
That was freaking transcendental, paul mccartney.
你能領會這些真是了不起  保羅·麥卡特尼
-don't you agree, john lennon? -yes, dewey cox.
-你同意嗎  約翰·列儂?  -我贊成  杜威·考克斯
With meditation there's no limit to what we can...
沉思可以讓我們無止境地...
...imagine.
...想像
What do you think, george harrison?
喬治·哈里森  你怎麼看?
L don't know. l'm just trying to get some more songs on the album, you know.
我不懂  你知道的  我只想再創作一些歌來充實這張專輯
And as ringo starr, l'm not so interested in meditation.
我對沉思不怎麼感興趣
L just like to have fun.
我只想找點樂趣
-l like the little one. -lt's so dark in this tent.
-我喜歡那個小個子  -這帳篷裡這麼黑
Reminds me when we, the beatles, the four beatles, us--
讓我想起當我們四個披頭士--
-from liverpool. -yes, we are from liverpool.
-來自利物浦  -對  來自利物浦
We used to play those dark clubs in hamburg.
我們在漢堡的那些黑暗的俱樂部裡演奏的時候
Remember that, paul?
你還記得嗎?  保羅
Of course l do, l booked them. l'm the leader of the beatles.
我當然記得  我是頭  是我聯繫的
Well, l have to say l like your stuff. lt's pretty good.
我必須得說  我很喜歡你們的音樂
And most of your records, l really enjoy.
真的非常喜歡你們的唱片
We're big fans of your records too.
我們也很喜歡你的唱片
We like to think that hard day's night is our guilty as charged.
我們喜歡把那些艱難的日子看成是"被審判的過錯"
-great record. -excellent album.
-非常好的唱片  -了不起的專輯
-we learned a lot from you. -great record.
-我們從你那裡學了不少  -非常好的唱片
-we're big fans of y'all. -huge fans.
-我們是你們所有人的忠實聽眾  -真的
You're almost as good as the monkees. you guys are great.
你們基本上和頑童合唱團一樣好  真了不起
L think l might adjourn to another dimension, take some lsd.
我想我該吃點藥  去另一個歡樂的世界
-do you care to join me? -yeah, let's do that.
-你們也要來點嗎?  -我們也來吧
Care to join us for some lsd? lt's good for you.
來點吧?  很不錯的
-built by scientists, it is. -lysergic.
-科學字發明的  -迷幻藥
Gotta check with headquarters.
我得問問老婆
Come on, dewey cox. think you might enjoy it.
來嘛  杜威·考克斯  你會喜歡的
Open your mind to a new experience, a new level of consciousness...
敞開心扉迎接新的體驗  一種全新的感覺...
...like we do, because we are the beatles.
...就像我們披頭士一樣
Why not let him decide. lf he wants to take lsd, he'll take it.
讓他自己做決定  如果他想要  他就會嗑的
He doesn't have to listen to you. you're not the boss of him.
他不用聽你的  你又不是他老大
Don't tell me what to say and what not to say, paul mccartney.
不用你來教我  保羅·麥卡特尼
L'm sick of you being so dark when l'm so impish and whimsical. l'm sick of it.
你這麼陰暗顯得我很怪  我真受不了你
Hey, everyone, we got a brand new mansion.
嘿  大家聽著  我們碰到了奇觀了
Paul's a big fat cunt.
保羅是一個又壯又肥的婊子
Don't know why you don't let me write more songs.
為什麼我們不讓多寫點歌呢?
You know, l just sit here while me guitar quietly whimpers, you know.
我只想靜靜的坐著  輕輕的彈吉他
You are the quiet one, so why don't you shut the fuck up?
既然你那麼安靜  現在你也給我閉嘴
L've got a song about an octopus.
我剛想到一首關於章魚的歌
Jam it up your ass. you're lucky we still let you play drums.
堵住你的鳥嘴  我們能讓你擊鼓已經是很大的幸運了
Wow, seems like there's a rift happening between the beatles.
他們之間有裂痕了
L wonder if your songs will still be shit when l'm 64.
當我64歲的時候不知道你的歌是不是還像屎一樣
-great sod. -no, stop it!
-混帳  -停下!
You bastard! you sissy.
雜種! 笨蛋!
Beatles. please stop fighting here in lndia.
披頭士  這裡是印度  不要打架
No, no, let them go. let them work it out.
別管他們  讓他們自己解決吧
Taste it.
嘗嘗看
Right there in the bollocks.
就在瓶子裡
-bastard! -cunt!
-雜種!  -婊子!
Dewey, you been living clean for three years now...
杜威  你三年都沒有碰過毒品了...
...and it's done you a world of good, has it not?
...這也帶給你很多好處  不是嗎?
L know l've had trouble with drugs in the past.
我知道過去因為吸毒惹了不少麻煩
But l'm addicted to coke, weed, booze, ludes and speed. not lsd.
我以前嘗過各種毒品  但從來沒有嘗過迷幻藥
Nobody gets addicted to lsd.
沒有人會對迷幻藥上癮的
Lt was invented by scientists. ringo starr just told me.
這是科學家發明的  瑞格·斯達剛告訴我的
L heard that doing lsd can awaken your demons.
我聽說迷幻藥會喚醒人心中的惡魔
L ain't got no demons gonna get woke.
我的心裡才沒有惡魔
Lf you promise it'll just be this one time.
如果你要保證僅此一次
Okay.
你可以嘗一下
Let's go drop acid with the beatles.
那我們去跟披頭士們拿藥去吧
Hello, dewey.
你好  杜威
Welcome to your lsd trip.
歡迎來到迷幻之旅
Where everything's a cartoon.
這是一個童話般的世界
We're the trippy cartoon beatles.
我們是神奇的披頭士
Look at that. lt's a flying fish.
看呀  一條會飛的魚
Totally trippy!
真奇妙!
Wow, this lsd's all right.
哇  太棒了
L like being a trippy cartoon.
我真喜歡這裡
Just keep thinking happy thoughts, dewey.
杜威  盡量去想些高興的事
L'd hate for this to turn into a bad trip.
我不想把它變成一次糟糕的經歷
What's that scary music?
那嚇人的聲音從哪來的?
L had an unhappy thought.
我有一個不高興的念頭
Lt's a bad trip.
這是一段糟糕的旅程
Bad trip, bad trip!
糟糕  糟糕!
Help! trippy machete!
救命! 砍刀!
Oh, fuck me. l can see my large colon.
該死  我看見我的腸子流出來了
L guess l do have some demons.
我想我心中確實存在著惡魔
You all right, cox?
你還好嗎  考克斯?
L don't know.
我不知道
Do you want some more lsd?
再來點藥嗎?
Yeah. l think l do.
好  我還要
Mr. schwartzberg, you're his long-time manager. maybe you can talk to him.
施沃爾伯格先生  你認識他這麼久了  你應該勸勸他
Well, what's the problem?
哦  有什麼問題?
He's been on that trampoline for four days.
他在蹦床上跳了4天了
You have got to talk some sense into him. l'm worried.
我很擔心  你得去說服他別再這樣了
Dewey, as your manager, l have to tell you l'm concerned.
杜威  做為你的經濟人  我不得不告訴你我很憂心
L think the lsd has changed you.
迷幻藥已經改變了你
Lt has changed me. lt's opened my mind right up.
它確實改變了我  它擴展了我的視野
L'm reinventing music.
我在重新創作音樂
L'm creating something new that l call ''shmusic.''
我給它取了一個新名字  shmusic
You've recorded the same song for eight months.
這一首歌你已經錄了8個月了
you're not close to finished.
連一點完成的跡象都沒有
Because this record is different than any other l've made.
因為這首歌與以往的都不同
L told you. this is going to be my masterpiece.
聽我說  這將成為我的最好的作品
The one l'm remembered by. lt's for my brother.
它會讓我在史上留名  它也是為我哥而創作的
What brother?
你哥?
Nothing. never mind. lt's private.
沒什麼  隱私而已
L've got this sound in my head and it's trying to get out.
這首歌在我腦子裡已經很久了  馬上就要出來了
L can't find it on this human plane of existence. l've got to keep on searching.
我還得再找一些東西才能創作出來
But l'll tell you what, l'm gonna find it.
我馬上就要找到了
You guys should make friends. he's a wonderful man.
你們應該認識一下  他是一個很不錯的人
Professor, good morning. all right, everyone. thank you.
教授  早上好  大家停一下  謝謝
L've just been outside, l had a little bounce.
我剛才在外面跳了一會兒
What we're going to do is run through the entire piece...
我們將要做的就是...
...in our minds, silently.
...在我們心裡靜靜的完成這段樂章
And...
好吧...
...begin.
現在開始...
As we sit here together on thanksgiving...
當我們一起坐在...
...on our beautiful trampoline...
這漂亮的蹦床上慶祝感恩節...
...l think we should take a moment to think about what it's like to be a turkey.
我們應該想像一下做為一隻火雞是什麼樣子的...
Gobble, gobble, gobble. gobble, gobble, gobble.
加波  加波...
hi, l'm just a little turkey.''
大家好  我是一隻小火雞
Just cut the damn bird, boy.
孩子  把火雞切了吧
Dewey? can we just enjoy our thanksgiving dinner?
杜威? 讓我們好好的享受晚餐  好嗎?
You think you're so great sitting there all drugged up...
你嗑了藥  在蹦床上跳...
...on your trampoline.
就覺得自己很偉大...
You're the black sheep of this family.
你真是個敗家子
You call yourself a cox.
你叫考克斯
Until you get right with jesus...
如果你不得到上帝的寬恕...
...you'll never be nothing but a big, black cox.
你永遠不是真正的考克斯
Nothing l do will ever please you, will it?
我做的任何事都讓你不滿意  是嗎?
We're both cox, pa. both of us are cox.
我們都叫考克斯  爸爸
L've got 1 3 7 musicians waiting on me.
我得失陪一下
You'll have to excuse me.
有137個音樂家在等我呢
Dewey, watch the turkey.
杜威  小心那只火雞
I wasn't dreaming
不是做夢
Barely awake
完全清醒
Off to the grinder we stroll
我們走到磨坊
This is not a good song.
這歌不好
Lt's like five songs on top of each other at the same time.
像5首歌交疊在一起
Not even a song. lt's some kind of concerto.
這不能叫歌  只是協奏曲
Just let him work it out.
讓他做完再說吧
Masterpieces take time.
好事總是多磨
Do you hear that? that goat's been singing...
你聽見了嗎? 在這首歌裡...
...more than l am on this damn song.
那隻羊比我唱得還多
Well?
怎麼樣?
That was beautiful, dewey. lt was perfection.
太棒了  杜威  太完美了
Yeah, even the goat was perfect.
是啊  那隻羊做的好很好
Yeah, the goat was good. were the strings tangy enough?
羊不錯  那弦聲怎麼樣  夠緊張嗎?
Oh, they were tangy. they were very tangy.
很緊
Unbelievably tangy.
難以置信的緊張
No, guys, the strings were not tangy! they were salty!
不對  夥計們  弦聲太軟了
Am l crazy?
我是不是瘋了?
Let's do one more time. okay, strings, lean into it.
讓我們再做一次  絃樂手  進入到音樂中來
L want it really tangy this time. now, mike, you're flatting.
我需要它再緊一點  邁克  你拉的就很平
Bushmen, make it sound like you're in the fucking bush, okay?
野人們  發出些叢林裡原始的聲音來  行不?
Back off the goat on the second pre-chorus.
撤掉第二次合聲中的羊聲
L wanna hear his heart, not his soul.
我要聽它的心  不是它的靈魂
Sam, go back to that thing you did yesterday on the bridge.
薩姆  回到你昨天在橋上做的那些東西來
-what did l do? -lt sounded like velvet pancakes.
-我做了什麼來了?  -聽起來像天鵝絨薄餅
-yeah, right. -okay, everybody, one more time.
-好  -好  大家再來一次
What on earth is a velvet pancake?
天鵝絨薄餅到底是什麼?
Lt's the lsd. l think it's having an effect on him.
是迷幻藥  我想是迷幻藥讓他變成這樣的
From the top of the overture. slate it.
在前奏前就打擊他
black sheep,'' take 1 1 2.
黑羊  第112次
I just close my eyes when I fantasize
閉上雙眼  開始冥想
Much to my surprise I'm only half the size
萬分新奇
That I used to be
我變得只有自己原來一半大小
Bye-bye, white brother
拜拜  白兄弟
This black sheep gotta roll
黑羊要走了
Lt's on the beat!
抓住節奏
I just open up like a catacomb
打開了一個墓穴
Though my heart is half from the half-f tone
我的心跳減了一半
That tickles.
這樣真癢
Bye-bye, pastures of plenty
拜拜  青青的綠草
I don't know where I will
我不知道我會飄向哪裡
-roam -black sheep, black sheep
黑羊  黑羊
Like that, with some urgency.
像這樣  好像有點急事
Not, ''l'm in the yard. l wanna go outside.''
我在院子裡  我想出去
Like, ''l'm about to die.'' like that.
就像  我馬上要死了
The blade has been swung
刀已經磨好
Black sheep, black sheep
黑羊  黑羊
All right? here we go.
好啊  我們開始
Push. push, baby, push.
使勁  使勁  親愛的  使勁
-are we recording this? -no.
-我們有對這個錄音嗎?  -沒有
Well, we should be. get a microphone. push, baby.
我們應該錄下來  去拿麥克  使勁  寶貝
Push.
使勁
Push! push!
使勁!  使勁!
I'm losin' my fleece from tryin'
我不斷嘗試  掉了不少毛
I'm losin' no sleep I'm dyin'
我整天睡覺  我快要死了
Why shouldn't I keep from cryin'?
我為什麼不能停止哭泣?
Cryin'
哭泣
I'm losin' my fleece from tryin'
我不斷嘗試  掉了不少毛
I'm losin' no sleep I'm dyin'
我整天睡覺  我快要死了
Why shouldn't I keep from cry--?
我為什麼不能停止哭泣?
Lt's still not finished yet.
還沒有完成
L'm hearing more aboriginal percussionists.
我想加入一些更原始的聲音
And l want an army of didgeridoos. fifty thousand didgeridoos!
我要很多很多的迪吉裡杜管  要五萬個
Folks, can we have a moment with dewey?
大家  可以讓我們跟他說句話嗎?
What the hell are these songs about?
這到底是什麼歌?
You're singing about cutting people in half--
你唱到把人切成兩半--
L'm working something out. lt's called a metaphor.
我正在創造新的東西  這是個隱喻
Well, what are you working out?
哦  那麼你要創造什麼?
Lt's secret. that's why it's called metaphor.
這是個秘密
That's what metaphor means. secret.
隱喻就是秘密
L just don't see why you gotta throw away the recipe, is all.
我不明白為什麼不用以前的那些創作方法
Why don't we just go in there, lay down some tracks like we always done?
用老方法老調子就簡單多了
Yeah, why can't we just walk hard?
對  為什麼不能像《永不停步》一樣呢?
What do we need all these people for?
為什麼要找這麼多人來呢?
L don't need people around me stifling me.
我不需要你們來指責我
So if you don't like it, there's the door.
如果你們不喜歡  現在就可以走
Dewey?
杜威?
Are you saying you don't need us no more?
你是指你再也不需要我們了?
Not unless you can open your mind and learn to play the fucking theremin.
除非你們都能解放思想按我的方法創作
Fuck you, dewey!
混蛋  杜威!
Yeah, fuck you, dewey.
混蛋  杜威
Ln 20 years not once have you thrown a woman on my way.
這二十多年來你不曾一次把女人推到我面前
You don't think we like cheating on our wives too?
我們也很喜歡在外面搞女人的
And you never once paid for drugs.
而且你從來沒有請客吸毒品
not once!
一次也沒有
You pay that chimp more than you pay us.
你對那只黑猩猩都比對我們好
L had to borrow from the chimp to get a mortgage on my house.
我不得不向黑猩猩借錢才能買房子
And those stupid siamese glass cats you get us every year for christmas.
還有你每年聖誕送給我們的暹羅的笨貓
L don't want any more siamese glass cats!
我再也不想要這些東西了
The siamese cat is a symbol of nobility in ancient egypt.
在古埃及暹羅貓代表著高貴
Fuck nobility!
去你的!
Fuck ancient egypt.
去你的古埃及
Fuck cats!
去你的貓!
And you never paid for drugs.
你從來不付錢買毒品
Not once.
一次也沒有
You slept with my wife.
你幹過我老婆
You slept with me too!
你也"干"了我
And l've had confused feelings about that for 1 0 years now!
從那之後到現在10年了  一直都感到很彆扭
And you never once paid for drugs.
你從來不付錢買毒品
Not once.
一次也沒有
You're on your own, dewey cox.
你自己幹吧  杜威·考克斯
We're leaving.
我們離開你了
Well, l guess this is the end of a chapter in your life,
我想你生命裡的一章應該結束了
Dewey cox.
杜威·考克斯
What's happened to you, dewey cox?
杜威·考克斯  你怎麼啦?
Stay out of this, darlene!
不要你管!
You're driving away the people who love you most!
你把那些最愛你的人都趕走了!
L don't need anybody, darlene.
我誰也不需要  戴琳
All l need is my music.
我有音樂就夠了
This ain't about your music, dewey. lt's about the drugs.
杜威  這跟音樂沒有關係  全是毒品害的
Honey, l told you l'm gonna quit again.
親愛的  我告訴過你我會戒毒的
As soon as the record's done. whenever that is.
只要錄完了這張唱片  錄完就戒
Look, you can't rush a masterpiece.
好作品都是急不來的
You need to take a break. you need to clean yourself up, otherwise--
你得停一下  你要先戒毒  否則--
Otherwise what?
否則什麼?
Otherwise l can't be married to you no more.
否則我就會跟你離婚
L know you don't mean that.
我知道你是開玩笑的
L believe you know that l do.
這不是玩笑
Okay.
好吧
-okay? -okay.
-真的?  -真的
You'll take a break?
你會停下來?
L will take a break.
我就停下來
And you'll quit the drugs?
你也會戒毒?
And l will quit the drugs.
我會的
Dewey!
杜威!
Oh, baby. l've been praying about this day for so long.
寶貝  我一直在祈禱這一天的到來
-what did you just put in your mouth? -gum.
-你剛才把什麼放到嘴裡了?  -口香糖
-you ain't chewing no gum. -candy?
-你從來不吃口香糖  -水果糖?
-what did you put in your mouth? -lt's pcp.
-到底是什麼?  -天使粉
Oh, you just said--!
天啦  你剛才還說--!
L'm going to town!
我要去鎮上!
Get out of the road, you jerk!
滾開  白癡!
Hey! what's going on?
你在幹嘛?
There he is!
他在那裡
Dewey! get off that building! lt's inappropriate!
杜威  不要爬上去  你不能那麼做
Dewey cox, you give me no choice.
杜威·考克斯  你讓我沒有選擇
Lt breaks my heart, but l'm leaving you.
你這麼讓我傷心  我只有離開你
L'm zeus!
我是宙斯
No mortal can stop me! l'm zeus!
沒人能阻止我  我是宙斯
-rehab? -rehab.
-恢復?  -恢復恢復吧
Nate!
內特!
Nate?
內特?
This is what l'd look like if l'd grown up...
我長大了就是這個樣子
...and perhaps hadn't been murdered, or whatever.
如果我沒有被謀殺的話
L just came to tell you you need to get your shit together!
我只是來告訴你  你需要好好整理一下你自己
L know.
我知道
L've fallen again.
我又倒下了
Listen to yourself. whining like a little bitch.
看看你自己  像個女人一樣抱怨
Lf l was alive right now,
如果我現在活著
l'd be the fucking president of the united states.
我可能會是他媽的美國總統
L'd be on the moon, walking around looking for aliens to kill.
我可能會在月球上  四處找外星人來殺
what?
什麼?
You know why dad liked me better?
你知道為什麼爸爸喜歡我多一些?
Because l was better than you.
因為我比你強
When l played the piano,
我彈琴的時候
l was fucking awesome.
我實在是太他媽牛啦
Well, you think it's been easy for me?
你認為我過的很好嗎?
Since you're gone l got no sense of smell.
你死了以後我就沒有嗅覺了
Oh, you got no sense of smell?
你沒有嗅覺了?
You can't smell anything? you can't smell anything?
你聞不到任何東西?  你聞不到任何東西?
L got no sense of having legs, dewey!
我連腿都沒有啦!  杜威
L have no life! l'm dead because somebody...
我沒有生命  我被人殺死
...l'm not gonna point out names right now...
我現在不想說殺我人的名字
...decided to murder me with a machete.
但是他用大砍刀把我謀殺了
-nate. -l can't even smell, touch, feel.
-內特  -我不能聞  觸摸  感覺
L can't even masturbate. you ever try to jerk off with a ghost hand?
我甚至不能手淫  你見過鬼手淫的嗎?
Nothing!
我什麼都沒有
L'm just trying to say you need to fix this shit.
我只是想告訴你你需要搞定這些
You need to get out of that bathtub. start writing songs again.
你需要從浴缸中起來  趕緊去寫歌
Ls he almost done thinking about his life?
他經常這麼思考人生嗎?
He just reached the '70s.
他都已經70歲了
Schwartzy, l don't know.
施沃爾  我不知道
l don't know, l don't know what's going on with me.
我不清楚我到底怎麼了
L got the song block.
我寫歌遇到瓶頸了
Song block.
寫歌的瓶頸?
L don't need to write any new songs.
我不需要去寫任何新的歌
L'll just do my old ones.
我就只唱我的老歌
we'll do a oldies tour
我們就用以前的曲目
l'll do ''walk hard.''
我可以唱"用不止步"
Dewey, ''walk hard'' is over 20 years old.
杜威  ''用不止步''已經唱了20年了
Well, a lot of people like my old songs.
可是很多人喜歡我的老歌
Old people like your old songs.
只有老人喜歡你的老歌
May l make a suggestion?
我可以給你一個建議嗎?
Are you familiar with the donny & marie show?
你聽說過湯尼&瑪麗的節目嗎?
-the television show? -l got a call from cbs.
-電視節目? -電視台打電話找過我
They wanna do the same kind of show with you.
他們給你搞一個差不多的電視節目
L'm a serious musician. l'm not some tv personality.
我是一個真正的音樂家  我不是什麼電視名人
Well, why can't you be both?
可你為什麼不能兩邊都做呢?
Look at those goofy bastards on hee haw.
你看電視裡的那些傻瓜們
Well, l do love hee haw.
其實我喜歡電視展示的
Television, dewey. lt's the way into the people's hearts.
杜威  電視是一種深入人心的方法
All right. you call them back today...
好的  你今天給他們打電話
...and you tell mr. cbs...
你告訴電視台先生
...that l will do it if l have total creative control.
如果我能全部做主創新的話  我就去做
Dewey, you can't have any creative control.
杜威  你不能做主任何事
Okay.
好吧
All right, let's just do it then. fuck it, let's do it.
好吧  我們干吧
L'm bored.
我太無聊了
Live from burbank, california.
來自加利福尼亞昆士蘭州的現場表演
It's the dewey cox show.
這就是杜威·考克斯的現場表演
And now your host, dewey cox!
杜威·考克斯  現在這裡你是主角了
-walk hard -hard
-用不止步
-hard -hard
-永不  -永不
Down life's rocky road
踏在  崎嶇的人生路上
-walk bold -bold
-步伐勇敢  -勇敢
-hard -hard
-堅定  -堅定
That's my creed
這是我的信念
My code
我的準則
I been scorned and slandered and ridiculed too
我被輕蔑過  誹謗過  嘲笑過
Had to suffer every day my whole life through
每天的生活  掙扎著
Seen my share of the worst that the world can give
看著世界扔給我的爛攤子
But I still got a dream and a burnin' rage to live
但我帶著夢想與狂暴繼續活著
Walk hard
永不止步
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen. welcome to the show.
謝謝大家  女士們先生們  歡迎來到現場
We've got a great one for you tonight.
我們今晚的節目將會很精彩
To get things rolling, l'd like to bring out my first guest...
現在我將請出我的第一位客人
Miss cheryl tiegs.
謝麗爾·提格絲女士
Well, hello, cheryl. don't you look lovely tonight.
你好  謝麗爾  你今天看起來真可愛
Well, thanks so much, sir. so do you.
非常感謝  你也很可愛
Cheryl, you know, you remind me of a 1 9 7 7 corvette.
謝麗爾  你知道嗎  你讓我想起了1977的雪佛蘭
Why is that?
為什麼?
Because you're a beautiful new model.
因為你是一個漂亮的模特(model也有車型的意思)
Just kidding.
開個玩笑啦
Would you do me the honor of joining me for a song?
你能跟我一起唱個歌嗎?
Well, l thought you'd never ask, mr. cox.
考克斯先生  我還以為你不會問我呢
Baby, come as you are with just your heart
寶貝  跟你的心一起來吧
And I'll take you in
我會帶你一起
You're rejected and hurt
你拒絕了我  傷害了我
To me you're worth what you have within
對於我你值得擁有
You don't have to be a star, baby
你不需要是個明星  寶貝
To be in my show
來我的現場演示吧
Good night, everybody. we'll see you next week.
大家晚安  我們下周再見
Good show.
表現不錯
-you ready, dewey? -yes, l'm ready.
-杜威  你準備好了嗎?  -是的  我準備好了
Who wants to party?'' dewey, lead vocal, take one.
誰想來派對?  音樂  第一次錄製
Hey, hey who wants to party?
誰想來派對?
Hey, hey who wants to party now?
誰現在一起來派對?
L don't know. l'll see you in a minute.
我不知道  我一會見你
All right. everybody good? everybody good?
所有人都過的好嗎?
Whoa, dewey. great party, great party.
杜威  派對非常棒  派對非常棒
Thanks, patrick duffy from dallas.
謝謝  達拉斯的帕特裡克·達夫
listen, mingle, enjoy yourself.
聽著  好好享受吧
-have sex with anybody you want. -well, can do.
-你可以和這裡任何一個人做愛  -絕對服從
-hey! -dewey!
杜威
Oh, my god, your show is such a hit.
上帝呀  你的表演太棒了
You beat mccloud last week.
上星期你打敗了邁克勞德
Well, thank you, morgan fairchild,
摩根·費爾切爾德  謝謝你
You know l never pay attention to the ratings.
你知道我從來不關注排名
Just kidding.
開個玩笑
we're gonna take a shit on donnie & marie.
我們一定在湯尼&瑪麗上面好好表演一下
-oh, you do that, honey. -yes.
-你做得到的  親愛的  -是的
Hey, you. are you gonna save a dance for me, dewey?
杜威  可以和我跳個舞嗎?
Well, you bet, cheryl ladd from charlie's angels.
查爾斯的天使謝麗爾·萊德  當然可以
Hey there, little miss cox-tiegs.
小考克斯·提格絲女士
Have you met my new wife, cheryl cox-tiegs?
你見過我的新妻子謝麗爾·考克斯提格絲嗎?
We've met, yes.
是的  我們見過
Lsn't that funny? you're both named cheryl.
真好玩  你們都叫謝麗爾
Yeah. we're aware of that.
我們都知道這個
That is hilarious.
這太好笑了
Hey, hey who wants to party?
誰要來派對?
L don't know what they're talking about with this energy crisis.
我不知道他們談論的精力危機是什麼
Because l have plenty of energy, all right? l am loaded with energy.
因為我精力旺盛  不是嗎?  我渾身充滿精力
Look, l gave up politics a long time ago.
你們看  我放棄政治有很長時間了
You know, let somebody else march. l wanna play frisbee.
你看  讓其他人行進  我想玩飛盤
L'm on the beach. l'm not marching on the beach.
我在海邊  我沒有朝海邊走
Billy, don't be a hero
比蒂  不要做英雄
Don't be a fool with your life
不要跟你的生活開玩笑
Do me, dewey.
干我  杜威
L can't, cheryl ladd, l'm married to cheryl tiegs.
我不能  謝麗爾·萊德  我和謝麗爾·提格絲結婚了
Oh, l should've been your guest star last week instead of her.
上星期我應該代替她來做你的嘉賓
Lt could've been me.
那就應該是我了
lt could've been me.''
應該是我
It could have been me could've been me
應該是我  應該是我
Stay in it. stay in it.
停一下  停一下
It could've been me
應該是我
Rocky ro..
崎嶇的...
No! you're repeating yourself!
不  你在重複你自己
Why can't l write a fucking song anymore?
為什麼我不能寫一個更牛的歌呢?
I love the nightlife I got to boogie
我喜歡夜晚的生活  我要跳迪斯科
On the disco 'round
在迪斯科地板上起舞
I told you I love the nightlife
告訴你  我喜歡夜生活
I got to boogie
我要跳迪斯科
On the disco 'round oh, yeah
在迪斯科地板上起舞
L'll tell you, l've never been so truly satisfied.
我告訴你  我從來沒有這麼滿足過
Living here in this beautiful beach house with you...
能在這個美麗的海景房裡面和你
...my beautiful cheryl cox-tiegs.
我美麗的謝麗爾·考克斯提格絲在一起
The ratings are great. these are the salad days.
排行榜非常棒  這是多麼甜蜜的日子呀
Yeah, l've been looking for something my whole life, and this is it.
我一生都在尋找  現在終於找到了
L'm finally truly satisfied.
我終於感到滿意了
Goodbye, love
再見吧  我的愛人
You are not going home. you are sleeping in the guestroom.
你不准回家  你要在客房裡睡
Forever.
永遠
Because you're the only one who stuck around.
因為你是唯一還來這裡的人
Everyone else got sick of it and left...
因為其他人都厭倦了  然後走了
...but you stuck around, which means you're my friend.
但是你留在了那裡   所以你是我的朋友
There's a starman waiting in the sky
這裡有個外星人等待在天空
He'd like to come and meet us
他期待能來這裡與我們碰面
But he thinks he'd blow our minds
但是他認為他吹動我們的心靈
There's a starman waiting in the sky
這裡有個外星人等待在天空
He's told us not to blow it cause he knows it's all worthwhile
他告訴我們不要吹它   因為它物超所值
He told me
他告訴我
Let the children use it let the children lose it
讓我們的孩子使用它  讓我們的孩子丟掉它
Let all the children boogie
讓所有的孩子跳迪斯科吧
Goddamn it!
媽的
L mean, what do l have to do to get you on my bone?
我的意思是我需要做什麼來得到我的骨頭呢?
lnvent fire?
發明火?
And then huge laugh and we go to commercial.
我們大笑  然後進廣告
all right, take five.
好了  休息5分鐘
Great rehearsal, dewey. very funny sketch.
偉大的排練  杜威  非常有趣的初稿
Thank you. have you seen the ratings?
謝謝  你看了排行榜嗎?
We're getting our ass kicked by the incredible hulk.
我們竟然被不可思議的公牛追上了收視率
Well, last night's episode was a very special episode.
昨天的表演是一個非常特殊的表演
They revealed that the lncredible hulk has an evil twin.
他們透露那個不可思議的公牛有個魔鬼雙胞胎
And he's not green. he's red.
同時他不是綠色的  他是紅色的
L know. lt was amazing. did you see it?
我知道  太驚奇了  你看到了嗎?
You can't compete with that.
你不能和這個競爭
But we do need to do more promotion.
但是我們的確需要更多的推廣
Here's what we'll do.
這是我們要做的
We'll introduce people to the new dewey cox.
我們要給大家介紹一個全新的杜威·考克斯
L got a girl here to interview you.
我帶了個女的來給你做專訪
She's from the local affiliate in dallas.
他從達拉斯當地的機構來的
L don't know. l'm not so good on interviews.
我不知道  我這個裝扮不太適合見人
Bubbe, it's a puff piece. lt's very puffy.
老兄  很快很簡單
All you have to do is remind the audience...
你所要做的就是提醒觀眾
...you're not mainlining acid anymore.
你不再吸毒了
And the show, it's a lot of fun, right?
還有節目很好看  是吧?
-you're having fun. -yeah.
-你玩的很開心  -是的
Lt's on every thursday night after the local news.
節目時間是每週四晚新聞結束後
l'm not mainlining acid.''
我不再沉溺於毒品
-anymore. -oh, l'm not gonna promise that.
-永遠也不  -這我不敢保證
Whatever you're comfortable with.
只要你高興
l don't smoke angel dust anymore.
我不會在吸這些天使粉了
So don't be afraid.'' something like that?
所以別害怕  像這樣說嗎?
Why don't you tell us about your new tv program?
跟大家談談你新的電視節目吧
Gail, it's a variety show.
蓋爾  這是個多種風格的節目
l do a little bit of everything.
我們節目每一樣都做一點點
L do some singing, some dancing, chatting with the guests...
我唱唱歌  跳跳舞  和客人聊聊天
...the skits, the monologues, the comedy.
講講幽默故事  表演表演獨白  還有表演喜劇
Wonderful. comedy.
真棒  喜劇
Lt really is a lot of fun.
這是非常有趣的
We'll have more fun when we come back from this word from our sponsors.
廣告之後會有更多有趣的內容
Don't go away.
別走開
Okay, you know what, l gotta tell you
你知道嗎  我必須要告訴你
My heart goes out to you.
我完全能理解你
L know what it's like to be on a piece-of-shit television program...
我知道主持這些破爛節目是什麼樣的
-...because l'm hosting one right now. -excuse me?
-因為我現在主持的這個就是  -什麼?
Must wanna blow your fucking brains out, l'll bet. l know l do.
我打賭這些節目一定把你累的要死
And we're back with mr. dewey cox.
再次回到節目
We're talking about the fun he's having on his show.
我們正在討論他在節目中的樂趣
But right now, let's talk about your lovely wife, darlene.
現在  讓我們聊聊你可愛的妻子  戴琳
How's she doing?
她現在好嗎?
Darlene and l separated some years ago, gail.
戴琳和我分開好幾年了  蓋爾
Oh, okay. guess l didn't do my homework.
暈  我猜我沒事先做好功課
And to answer your question, l miss her terribly.
對於你的問題  我非常思念她
Well, that's sweet.
真是甜蜜
Why don't we talk about your parents?
為什麼我們不聊聊你的父母呢?
They've gotta be proud of you.
他們一定為你而驕傲
Well, my mom is dead.
我媽媽死了
And my pa and l don't speak to each other...
我爸爸和我互相不說話
...so we're not very close.
因此我們關係不是很好
We can always cut around this if it gets too pathetic.
我們可以把這段切掉  如果顯得太可憐的話
Tell us about your kids. l know you got a whole slew of them.
跟我們聊聊你的孩子  我知道你有一大群的小孩
L'm locked in a custody battle at this time.
此時我正糾纏在監護權的事情裡
Custody is being forced upon me,
我被強迫要承擔監護權
which l don't think is right.
這個我認為是不對的
You know, if you don't want the responsibility of children...
你知道  如果你不打算承擔小孩的責任
...you should be able to walk away...
你就應該能不負這個責任
...and apparently a couple of my ex-wives don't feel the same. so, yeah.
很明顯  我的幾個前女友不是這麼認為的
Wherever my kids are,
無論我的孩子在哪裡
they're watching the dewey cox show...
他們都在看杜威·考克斯的節目
...on thursday nights at 8:00, right after the local news.
這個節目在週四晚上8:00 當地新聞之後開始
And l just wanted to say to everyone out there...
我想對這裡的每個人說
...l'm no longer mainlining acid or smoking pcp.
我不再沉溺於毒品或者吸食冰毒了
Lt's official.
這是正式的
Okay. why don't we lighten it up just a bit here?
為什麼我們講點快樂的事情呢?
You're so busy, dewey cox
你非常忙  杜威·考克斯
Do you have time to stop and smell the roses?
你有時間停下來聞聞玫瑰花香呢?
L've got no fucking sense of smell.
我他媽的失去了嗅覺
All right, l'm done.
好了  我講完了
Come on, folks. do a little research.
兄弟們  做點功課
That would've been nice information.
這還真是有趣的個人信息啊
L'm sorry, l must be tired from the show or something.
我很抱歉  我肯定是做節目太累了
-lt's okay. -yeah, dewey, it's okay.
-沒事的  -沒事  杜威
No, it's not okay. l should be able to do this.
一點也不好  我應該可以做這個的
We're in no rush.
我們不急
Should we get an american lndian woman?
要不我們找個印第安女人?
No, that won't help. l mean
別  這無濟於事  我的意思是
It should already be pretty exciting.
它早該興奮起來了
There's three of you.
有你們三個
-dewey. -nate?
-杜威  -內特?
You were supposed to be double great. what the fuck is this bullshit?
你應該兩倍的好  現在是怎麼搞的?
-l know. -all l'm asking...
-我知道  -我只求你
...is that you write one masterpiece...
寫出一首傑作
...that is the culmination of your entire life.
那將是你整個人生的頂峰
How hard is that?
這很難嗎?
L'm empty, nate. what do l do?
我江郎才盡了  內特  我還能做什麼?
Dewey, who's the one person in your life
杜威  你生命中哪個人
Who's made you feel like shit?
讓你覺得自己一文不值?
-pa. -you need to talk to him, dewey.
-爸爸  -你需要跟他談談  杜威
-l don't know. -you need to hug him.
-我不知道  -你需要抱抱他
L have been putting this off my entire life...
我早就在我的生活中不考慮這些了
...but l think you might be right.
不過我認為你說的可能是對的
The wrong kid died
孩子死錯了
Hello, pa.
爸爸  你好
What do you want?
你要幹嘛?
L feel like there's some things l need to say to you.
我覺得我想跟你說些事情
Well, go on. talk.
好 說吧
L've realized that...
我明白
...l never really said l was sorry
關於內特的事
For what happened with nate.
我從來沒有真正向您道歉
Pa, l've spent my entire life...
爸爸  我花了一生的時間
...trying to find love with wives...
去尋找愛  和我的妻子
...and hotel clerks...
和酒店招待員
...and tollbooth attendants...
和收費站的服務員
...and giraffes and monkeys and trampolines...
和長頸鹿  和猴子  和蹦床
...and men who dress like women and men who look like you.
和穿得像女人的男人  以及長得像你的男人
And l realized the only person l've ever really wanted to love me...
我最終發現我真正想要的愛就
...was you, pa.
是你  爸爸
Dewey, l don't know what to say.
杜威  我不知道該說什麼
You don't have to say anything, pa.
你什麼也不用說  爸爸
L just wanted to come here and tell you that l loved you...
我只是到這裡告訴你我愛你
...and l always have.
而且永遠都愛你
L appreciate you finding the courage to say that, dewey.
我很欣賞你有勇氣來說這個  杜威
But there's only one way to settle this.
但是這裡只要一種方法可以解決它
-machetes. -what?
-大砍刀  -什麼?
The right kid is gonna die tonight.
該死的孩子今天晚上就要死了
You've been practicing!
你一直在練習!!
No, pa. no!
不  爸爸  不
L been waiting for this for a long time!
我等這一刻很長時間了
You have?
你真的?
Oh, no.
不  不
Oh, my goodness!
我的上帝呀
L halved myself.
我把自己砍成兩段了
Pa! no, pa!
爸爸  不  爸爸
Dewey, l guess l never realized until this moment...
杜威  此時此刻我才終於明白
...just how easy it is to accidentally cut someone in half.
把人砍成兩段是這麼的容易
Lt is, right?
你也這麼覺得吧
L'm sorry for blaming you, dewey.
杜威  我很抱歉一直責備你
Of course you didn't mean to cut nate in half.
當然你不是故意把內特砍成兩段
Lt's all so obvious now.
現在我已經很清楚了
Pa.
爸爸
L should've been a better father to you, dewey.
杜威  我本可以做一個更好的父親
L wish l spent more time playing catch with you...
我希望我能有更多的時間和你一起玩棒球
...and less time training my body and mind
少一點時間訓練我的身體和心理，
To kill you in a machete fight.
為了用大砍刀來殺你
You be a better father than l was, dewey.
杜威  你要做一個比我好的爸爸
L'll try, pa.
我會盡力的 爸爸
Lt shouldn't be that hard.
這應該不會很難
Ln case l don't make it--
如果我死的話
Pa! you're gonna make it! lt's the 1 9 70s!
爸爸  你不會死的  現在是1970年
They got all kinds of new procedures that can attach tops to bottoms now!
他們有很多新的手術可以把身體連接起來
Hang in there! you're gonna be fine!
堅持  你會沒事的
L reckon you're probably right. now, go call the doctor...
我覺得你可能是對的   現在快去叫醫生吧
-...and bring me some ice, a lot of ice. -some ice.
再給我帶點冰快   帶很多很多冰塊
And a tourniquet. don't forget a tourniquet.
還有一個止血繃帶  別忘了帶止血繃帶
-all right, ice and a tourniquet? -lce and a tourniquet.
-好的  冰塊和止血繃帶?  -冰塊和止血繃帶
-and a tourniquet. -don't forget that tourniquet.
-還有一個止血繃帶  -別忘了帶止血繃帶
And you know those three words you always wanted to hear, dewey?
杜威  有3個字你一直想聽我對你說?
Well, here they are.
好吧  我現在說給你聽
L love....
我愛
You love what?
你愛什麼?
Pa, you love what?
爸爸  你愛什麼?
What was the third word?
第三個字是什麼呀?
Come on, one more word!
快呀  最後一個字
No!
不
L want all you fucking parasites out of my house...
你們這些寄生蟲滾出我的房間
...right now!
現在
L said, everybody out!
我說了  都滾
Well, look at you, you arrogant cocksucker.
看看你  你這個自負的王八蛋
-how dare you. -what happened to you, dewey?
-你竟敢罵我  -你怎麼了?  杜威
L don't know what's happened to me
我不知道我怎麼了
But l know what happened to you.
但是我知道你會怎麼樣
Patrick duffy took a beating.
帕特裡克·達夫  吃了我一拳
Stop it, dewey, you son of a bitch.
停手  杜威  你個狗娘養的
Stop it! patrick duffy was only saying what we were all feeling.
住手!  帕特裡克·達夫只是說出我們要說的而已
You get the hell away from me, cheryl cox-tiegs!
你給我滾遠點  謝麗爾·考克斯提格絲!
If you tear that sink off the wall, l'm leaving you.
如果你敢把洗手池弄壞  我就和你離婚
-oh, yeah? -yeah.
-哦  是嗎?  -是的
I'm leaving you, dewey cox.
那我只能和你離婚了  杜威·考克斯
No!
不要離開我!
Dad?
爸爸?
Yes, what is it, son?
怎麼了  兒子?
I was just wondering if you wanna have a catch.
我只是想知道你願不願意陪我玩球
A catch?
玩球?
Son...
我的寶貝...
...there is nothing in this world l want more...
...這個世上我再無所求
...than to have a catch with you.
...能陪你一起玩會兒球就足夠了
Son, forgive me, this is going to sound strange...
兒子  原諒我吧  也許這問題聽起來很怪...
...but what is your name again?
...你叫什麼名字了著?
I'm dewey junior, but my friends call me ''dewdrop.''
我叫杜威二世  不過我的朋友們都叫我"漏球威"
It's nice to formally meet you, dewdrop.
那麼能正式的認識你  我很高興  "漏球威"
So this is catch.
看  這樣就接住了
This is what l been missing out on all them years on the road, huh?
這就是我這麼多年來錯過的東西了  對不對?
I like it, it's wonderful. you throw it to me, l throw it back to you.
這感覺真不錯  你扔給我  我再扔給你
It's so simple, and yet so powerful.
一切都這樣簡單  又是這樣有趣
Boy, you're really terrible at this game.
孩子  你玩的可是夠爛的了
Well, l mean, you never really played with me before.
對啊  可是你以前從來沒陪我玩過啊
How am l supposed to learn? a boy needs a dad.
我又怎麼能學會呢?  兒子需要一個爸爸
Yes, he does.
嗯  的確如此
Well, l reckon we got some lost time to make up, you and me.
我會把那些本該和你還有你的兄弟姐妹
And all your brothers and sisters. how many of you are there?
共度的時光補回來的  你有多少兄弟姐妹?
Twenty-two brothers and sisters. and also 1 4 half-brothers and half-sisters.
22個表兄妹  還有14個同父異母的兄弟姐妹
Holy shit.
見鬼
This may take a while.
這可是要花點時間了
That's real good.
不錯
So beautiful.
幹的漂亮
Are you sure you're one of mine?
你真的是我的孩子嗎?
Go ahead and taste some dirt.
嘗嘗泥土的味道吧
That's good dirt. that's good dirt.
這土不錯  這土不錯
On the surface, macbeth is about revenge.
表面上來說  麥克白的故事是個復仇的故事
But what is the subtext?
但這個故事的隱喻是什麼呢?
A power struggle for the scottish royal family, that's what it is.
一個蘇格蘭王室間的鬥爭的故事
I just gave you it.
我已經教你了
Yeah.
好的
Hello, dewey.
你好啊  杜威
Darlene.
戴琳
It's dewina's birthday.
今天是杜威娜的生日
l brought her a present. lt's a bracelet.
這是我買的禮物  一副手鐲
How's glen campbell?
你和格蘭·坎貝爾過得怎麼樣?
He and l split up a long time ago.
我們很長時間以前就分手了
Really?
真的嗎?
It's just me these days.
這麼長時間以來我都是單身
At age 50.
50歲的單身女人
Would you care to take a walk with me, darlene madison?
能陪我散散步嗎?  戴琳·麥迪遜
I haven't been playing much music last few years.
我不在做音樂了
I realize now I wasn't much of a father
我終於意識到從前四處演出的時候
When l was out on the road.
我不是一個好父親
Now this is what makes me happy.
現在這一切都讓我開心
Not the music, not getting high...
不再做音樂  不再嗑藥...
...just my family.
...只有家庭
That's all I care about.
就是我想要的全部
And that family is missing one piece, darlene.
而這個家總是感覺少了點什麼  戴琳
My god, you're as beautiful as the day l met you.
老天  你還和我第一天遇見你一樣  那麼美麗
You don't want this dirty old cox.
你一定不想再要這個老考克斯了
Oh, I want it more than ever.
我更勝以往的想要你
Did you wash your hair today?
你今天洗頭了?
I sure did. how could you tell?
洗了  你怎麼知道的?
It smells terrific.
聞起來香極了
I smelt it.
我能聞到味兒了
You mean...?
你是說...?
I smelt it!
我能問道味兒了!
I can smell again!
我的鼻子又能聞到味道了!
-I smell you. -smell it.
-讓我聞聞你  -好好聞聞吧
Oh, you've been driving me wild.
哦  這味道讓我爽死了
I smelt it! I smelt it!
我聞到了!  我聞到了!
I smelt it, god!
我聞到了  上帝啊!
It's a miracle!
這真是一個奇跡!
I smell you, flowers.
我聞到你的香味了  花兒
I smell you, twig.
我聞到你的味兒了  樹枝(^_^)
I smell horseshit!
我聞到你的味兒了  馬屎(-_-!!!)
It's horrible!
這味兒可真臭
-but l can smell it! -smell that shit, baby!
-但是我聞到了!  -好好聞聞吧  寶貝!
I smelt it.
我聞到了
Anyway, that's when l learned...
總之  那時候我明白了
...that quaaludes and water-skiing do not mix.
吃安眠酮的時候不能衝浪
Now, you remember that.
現在  你一定要記住這個
How come you did all of that stuff, grandpa?
你為什麼做這些事情  爺爺?
Well, dewey rahim, I'll tell you. I was young and stupid then.
杜威·埃希米  那個時候很傻很天真
I didn't understand a lot of things.
很多事情都沒有想明白
Think it had to do with how l was reared as a boy.
也許這和我成長的環境有關係
But, you know, l got no complaints.
不過我沒什麼好埋怨的
It's been a beautiful ride.
對我來說那是一段光輝歲月
A beautiful ride?
光輝歲月?
A beautiful ride.
《光輝歲月》
Dewey, sweetheart, there's someone here to see you.
杜威  寶貝兒  有人要看你
Mr. cox.
考克斯先生
I'm sorry, have we met?
不好意思  我們見過面嗎?
You worked with my father, kvetch l'chaim.
你曾和我父親一起工作  科維奇·艾克萊姆
You're mr. l'chaim's boy?
你是艾克萊姆先生的兒子?
Dreidel l'chaim, that's me.
德瑞德爾·艾克萊姆  就是我
Well, it's nice to see you again, dreidel l'chaim.
能見到你真是太高興了  德瑞德爾·艾克萊姆
The pleasure's all mine.
那是我的榮幸才對
Listen, mr. cox, there's something l want to show you.
考克斯先生  我有一些東西要給你看看
I never rock a fella but I rock a cinderella
哥們給我滾開  娘們請你過來
While she's sittin' in between a nigga's legs like a cello
她像個大提琴坐在黑鬼腿中
Must be those pair of double-ds
她那對D罩杯的大波波
That got a nigga sittin' rock-hard in his jeans
讓那黑鬼在褲裡立正
Time to play make your mouth into a hole, yo
是時候到你表演嘴功
Tell me how I feel when I'm rockin' your boat
告訴我你是否享受其中
-i wanna make you fuckin' -hard
-我要讓你徹底立正  -硬!
I'm so wet, I gotta make you
我按耐不住  我想要你...
Hard
硬!
Mr. l'chaim, how could you allow them to do such a thing...
艾克萊姆先生  你怎麼能讓他們
...with my husband's music?
這樣糟蹋我丈夫的音樂?
Through the roof, we're selling.
那是《亡命天涯》 我們正在賣的唱片
Lil' nutzzak. that's the rapper. sweet kid.
那是Lil'nutzzak  說唱歌手  很可愛的孩子
Anyway, he's introduced a whole new generation...
他開創了一種和杜威·考克斯的老歌
...to the magic of dewey cox.
混音的新唱法
You could even play together.
你們應該同台演出
Cox and lil' nutzzak. what a package.
考克斯&lil'nutzzak 一個多麼炫的組合
Anyway, as if that was not enough...
還有個更好的消息
...they're giving dewey the lifetime achievement award next month.
他們下個月要給杜威頒發終身成就獎
The lifetime achievement award?
終身成就獎?
Baby, that's wonderful.
寶貝  那太棒了
You go on tv, they give you the award.
你將上電視接受頒獎
You play a song, it's a magical thing.
你可以唱歌  多棒啊
I can't go on tv and play.
我不能再上電視演出了
-what? why not? -why, grandpa?
-你說什麼?  為什麼不行?  -為什麼呢  爺爺?
Hell, I'm 7 1 years old. I don't even know if l can rock no more.
我都71了  我都不確定還能不能"搖滾"起來了
Of course you can rock, sweetheart.
你當然還能唱搖滾樂  親愛的
Well, l don't know that l can rock.
我想我是不行了
And besides that...
除了那個之外...
...l gave that life up for a reason.
我放棄那種生活是有原因的
I'm afraid of the temptations, darlene.
我怕再次墮於慾望  戴琳
You can do it, dewey.
你一定會戰勝慾望的  杜威
l know you can.
我知道你可以的
Just go out there and sing your song.
你只要登上台唱你的歌就行了
I'm gonna need my band.
我要重組我的樂隊
My hip.
我的屁股
Ladies and gentlemen...
先生們女士們
...please welcome jewel, lyle lovett and jackson browne.
讓我們歡迎朱爾  萊爾·拉維特&傑克森·布朗
Walk hard
永不止步
Hard
永不
Down life's
踏在崎嶇
-rocky road -rocky road
-人生路上  -人生路上
Walk bold
步伐勇敢
Hard
堅定
That's my creed
這是我的信念
-my code -my code
-我的準則  -我的準則
I been scorned and slandered and ridiculed too
我被輕蔑過  誹謗過  嘲笑過
Had to struggle every day my whole life through
每天的生活  掙扎著
Seen my share of the worst this world can give
看著世界扔給我的爛攤子
But I still got a dream and a burnin' rage to live
但我帶著夢想與狂暴繼續活著
Hello.
你好啊
Oh, he is so cute.
他太迷人了
What are you doing later, dewey?
一會兒不找點樂子嗎?  杜威
L am returning to the hotel with my family.
我得回旅館  我的家人等著我呢
Good night to you.
晚安
He fucked my grandma.
他上過我的祖母
That's awesome.
那真是太爽了
Ghostface killah.
鬼臉奇拉
Walking hard I'm a real hard walker
漫漫長路我累得要死
Fast on the trigger and a smooth talker
路上碰到的都是狗屎
My guns pop out like a jack-in-the-box I'll cut you in half like dewey cox
一槍爆頭把你打成杜威·考克斯
-walk hard -my skin stays scarred
-永不止步  -我渾身滿是傷痕
You can ask god
不信你去問問神
Lots of ladies unsnapped they bras
女人傻等我就是有去無回
Ask lyle lovett I had sex on mars
問問萊爾·拉維特我都睡過誰
That's how we do it when we walk hard
這一路艱辛誰還在乎誰?
-walk hard -how do I walk? hard as a stone
-永不止步  -漫漫征途  艱難困苦
How do I walk? hard like a bone
漫漫征途  艱難困苦
Tell me how we walk hard, hard, hard, hard
永不止步  永不止步  永不止步...
Oh, no. you're adorable.
哦  你太可愛了
Sam. what are y'all doing in here?
薩姆  你們在這幹什麼呢?
Dewey, get out of here. you don't want no part of this shit.
杜威  出去  你不會喜歡這鬼東西的
What is it?
那是什麼?
Lt's a medication for erectile dysfunction.
這是偉哥
Lt gives you a boner.
它會讓你爽翻了的
Not to be used if you have a heart condition.
要是你有心臟病就別吃了
Lf boners last for more than four hours, call more ladies.
如果你能挺4個小時的話  叫更多的妞過來(-_-!!)
Well, that does sound tempting.
那聽起來很有誘惑力啊
But do you know what, sam?
不過你知道嗎?  薩姆
l really don't want no part of that shit.
我確實不想再去碰那鬼東西了
Did you hear what l said? lt gives you a boner.
你沒明白我的話?  他會讓你廉頗不老
Hate to let you down, old friend...
我不想打擊你  老朋友
...but l don't wanna succumb to the temptations.
我不想再次墮於誘惑
-my girl -my girl
-我的寶貝兒  -我的寶貝兒
Talkin' 'bout my girl, yeah
說說我的寶貝兒吧
My girl
我的寶貝兒
The temptations!
誘惑!
When it's cold outside
天氣變冷了
I got the month of may
五月開始了
Do l still have what it takes?
我還能像以前那樣嗎?
Am l still the man l used to be?
我還是那個曾經的我嗎?
And do l even want to be?
我是不是還想要像從前那樣?
You're still dewey cox.
你始終都是杜威·考克斯
And you're the only man who ever will be.
你永遠都要做你自己
But is that enough?
我做的足夠好嗎?
Lt's more than enough.
應該說是非常好
Nate.
內特
Have l fulfilled my promise to be double great for the both of us?
我履行我要贏得雙倍成功的諾言了嗎?
Are you kidding? you've made 44 gold records.
那是當然了!  你有44張唱片賣到金唱片
You've been addicted to, and then kicked...
你嘗試過人類已知的每一種毒品
...almost every drug known to man.
又每一次都戒掉了
You slept with 41 1 women and three men.
你和411個女人上過床  另外還有3個男人
Dewey, you have had an awesome life.
杜威  你有著傳奇般的一生
L have, haven't l?
我做到了  是吧?
You sure have.
你當然做到了!
-pa. -son, you learned the hard way.
-爸  -兒子  你學會了在逆境下成長
You can't spend all your time thinking about dewey cox.
你不要所有的時間都想著自己
You gotta think about the world and your family.
你要想想這個世界和你的家人
But then, at the same time....
不過  同時...
Are you my inner child?
你是小時候的我嗎?
-yeah, dewey, l'm you. -he's us.
-是啊  杜威  我就是你  -他是我們倆
You realized you gotta take care of dewey cox.
你意識到了你得保護好杜威·考克斯
That's a little different than what l was saying.
那和我說的有些不同
You're all right.
你們說的都沒錯
Pa, inner child, nate, my own reflection.
爸爸  小時候的我  內特  我的鏡像
L've learned that l can't spend all my time thinking about dewey cox.
我已經明白了我不應該只想著我自己
And l've also learned l need to love dewey cox.
我也學會了去愛自己
L can't spend all my time thinking about other people.
我也不能光想著別人
L have to focus on myself.
我也要關心自己
But also not focus on myself and instead focus on other people.
但也不要因對自己關心而忽視別人的感受
Lt's all so clear now.
這一切已經很清楚了
Lt's not about yourself and other people.
不是你和其他人
-mama. -lt's about the music.
-媽媽  -是音樂
-lt's about the music. -lt always has been.
-是音樂  -永遠都是音樂
Lt always has been.
永遠都是
-who are you? -l'm your feminine side.
-你是誰?  -我是你性格中女性的那一面
L've been waiting for you to get in touch with me.
我期待和你交流很久了
We heard him sing about walking hard...
我們聽他唱過永不止步
...and we learned a little something about how we wanted to walk.
我們也學會了永不放棄
What do we think about when we think about cox?
我們在想到考克斯的時候心中是種什麼感覺?
He's been called the drifter.
他被稱作漂流者
Also the shape shifter, the master chef, the chameleon.
擅變者
The problem child. the hard one.
問題少年  頑強的代名詞
The white lndian. the giant midget.
白人中的印度人  侏儒中的巨人
Lf elvis and buddy holly are the cain and abel of rock 'n' roll...
如果說貓王&巴迪·哈利傅是搖滾界的亞當和該隱
...and bruce springsteen is zechariah...
布魯斯·斯普林斯廷是搖滾界的先知
...lggy pop is methuselah...
伊基·波譜是搖滾界的常青樹
...and, of course, neil young is the wise prophet ezekiel...
尼爾·楊是搖滾界的智者
...then what does that make dewey cox?
那麼杜威·考克斯又應該被稱作什麼呢?
Well, l don't know what god....
我不知道應該給與他怎樣的一個...
Mr. cox?
考克斯先生?
L don't wanna rush him, but he goes on in a minute.
我不想催他  不過他馬上就要上台了
Ladies and gentlemen, it is my great honor to introduce...
女士們先生們  做主持25年來...
...for the first time on-stage in 25 years...
...第一次將我最高的敬意致以
...performing his final masterpiece...
...即將帶來傾其一生的心血的...
...that will sum up his entire life...
...精彩演出的...
Mr. cox?
考克斯先生?
...the one, the only...
...我們永遠唯一的...
L'm ready.
我準備好了
...mr. dewey cox.
杜威·考克斯先生!
Thank you very much, ladies and gentlemen.
非常感謝  女士們先生們
You'll forgive me if l'm a bit rusty.
我可能會有點遲緩了  請原諒我這個老傢伙
This is the first song l've written in a very long time.
這是這麼長時間來我寫的第一首歌
L hope you enjoy it.
希望你們能喜歡
Now that I have lived
我度過了精彩的一生
A lifetime's worth of days
每天都是那樣的美妙
Finally I see
最後當我回首往事
The folly of my ways
我做過的那些傻事
So listen when I sing of
我唱過的那些老歌
The temptations of this world
原來都是慾念在作怪
Fancy cars and needles
財富  毒品  酒精  女人  榮耀
Whiskey, flesh and pearls
原來都是虛幻
And then in the end
到了最後才發現
It's family and friends
只有家人和朋友才是永遠
Loving yourself
愛惜自己
But not only yourself
還有你的生活
It's about the good walk and the hard walk
珍惜那些走過的幸福和痛苦
And the young girls you've made cry
那些為你心碎的女孩
It's about make a little music every day till you die
那些伴你一生的音樂
It's a beautiful ride
那真是一段光輝歲月
Beautiful ride
光輝歲月
Beautiful
光輝
As I stand on the precipice of death
當我直面死亡來臨
My perspective is enormous
我的世界開始變得清晰
Every leaf, every cloud
每片樹葉  每朵雲彩
I see the hands which have formed us
我看到了一雙雙緊握我們的手
And some days all you got
那些一段段共同走過的日子
Is a nighttime graveyard walk
在死去的那一天
And you whistle some sweet melody
我們也要哼出歡快的小調
To the ghosts down at the dock
為地下的那些故去的人
Sing into your hand
揮舞我們的手臂
Lead the marching band
來一場華麗的演出
Don't you let 'em fade your colors gray
別讓自己的生活黯然失色
Cause when all is said and done
為了那些說過的和做過的
When youth is spent and burned
當青春不再
You'll see that it's all about
精彩的日子依然在眼前浮現
Music
音樂
Flowers
鮮花
Babies
寶貝兒啊
Sharin' the good times
分享好時光吧
Travelin' not just for business
一起去旅行吧
Accepting your mortality
安靜的迎接死亡的降臨
This is finally what I've learned
那就是我最後明白的道理
And then in the end
最後的最後
It's family and friends
別忘你了的家人和朋友
Loving yourself
愛自己
But not only yourself
更要熱愛生活
It's about the good walk and the hard walk
那些走過的幸福和痛苦
And the young girls you've made cry
那些為你心碎的女孩
It's about make a little music every day till you die
那些伴你一生的音樂
It's a beautiful ride
那真是一段光輝歲月
Beautiful ride
光輝歲月
Beautiful
光輝
Dewey died three minutes after this performance
演出後3分鐘  杜威去世
Walk hard
永不止步
Hard
永不
Down life's
踏在
Rocky road
崎嶇的人生路上
Walk bold
步伐勇敢
Hard
堅定
That's my creed
這是我的信念
My code
我的準則
Walk hard
永不止步